<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Substance 3D on Pete Dimitrov&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/tags/substance-3d/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Substance 3D on Pete Dimitrov&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://petedimitrovart.com/tags/substance-3d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Amarantos Ritual - 02 - Reference</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos008-c.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Amarantos Ritual - 02 - Reference" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;novel-and-old-concepts&#34;&gt;Novel and Old Concepts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second entry of this series I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to explore my references and early inspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at lots of artists, games, and photographs from all kinds of places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start a new art idea its good to look at plenty of references. You can source your idea or inspiration by mixing together existing paintings, photos, short stories, books and more. It&amp;rsquo;s also integral to look at real life photos. We aim for believable and realistic spaces and layouts (or at least I do in this project). That is even when our subjects are fantastical. As such parts of what we are about to create needs to be grounded on reality. Those parts need to have roots in what is already familiar in the viewers eyes. Then on top you sprinkle bit of the eerie, unknown, novel and bizarre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-stage&#34;&gt;Current Stage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the previous blog (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;The Amarantos Ritual - 01 - Beginning&lt;/a&gt;) after figuring out my Houdini orb and that it will be the center piece of the composition and the layout, I was at this stage of the scene:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos007.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3162&#34;
	height=&#34;1779&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal 5 screenshot from the previous blog entry. A circular room with placeholder gray materials and strong orange glow. There is a fuzzy, liquid metal orb in the very middle. Around are pillars with ornate details on their tops. The walls have slight gaps for sci-fi-esque windows. There is a door that is slightly ajar and sunlight comes out of it.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did some further tweaks and added a little bridge platforms to connect the middle, circular platform to the outer edges of the room. In the very dead center, I cut a gap in order to place more &amp;ldquo;liquid metal&amp;rdquo; type of effect. I wanted to lead to the idea that perhaps in that basin in the middle of the room, there was an inactive substance. Few people, aliens, or some other creatures, enter the room and interact with that inactive substance. With their presence, it comes to life. It forms into the orb that then starts to float in the upper, middle point, space of the large room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you perhaps remember from the last entry, I really wanted to lead towards the idea of a ritual happening in this space. The creatures that enter the room bring the orb to life. They perhaps worship it, fear it, but are also astonished by it. Does it bring them energy? Food? Pleasure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the relationship between these characters and this &amp;ldquo;inanimate&amp;rdquo; object that the next moment seems to come to life and be lively?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I start new scenes, or any other type of art, I usually make up a few sentences that form a story. The moment I have that I start to ask questions. Those questions are very much like the ones above. They help me refine and see more than what there is at first in my mind. They help me make a 3D space that is more believable, interesting and rich in story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is an exercise I think you should try yourself. Whenever you create a layout, ask yourself why its the way it is? When you place props, ask yourself why they are there and what their relation to other objects around them is? Ask how you can tie up one item to another so they look more coherent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos008.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3162&#34;
	height=&#34;1779&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Another Unreal 5 screenshot. Camera angle is the same as the image above. This time the strong orange glow in the left parts of the circular room is removed. The gray, placeholder materials have a cooler tone in general as well. The liquid metal orb from Houdini still floats in the middle of the room, but the central platform is now connected by little bridges. There is a basin cut in the middle too, with darkness inside it.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into more screenshots inside this 3D space, lets take a step back. As mentioned in the start of this entry, I want to include my references and early influences behind the art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.pureref.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PureRef&lt;/a&gt; to put all of my reference images in one place. I like using this piece of software because it&amp;rsquo;s very lightweight. Some people use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://miro.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Miro&lt;/a&gt; which has a similar idea but more annotation tools, sticky notes and other cool features. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that PureRef is easier on the RAM than having a webpage open or using the Miro desktop software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my ref board I make sure to mix plenty of 2D art, 3D art but also real life photographs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos009.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;973&#34;
	height=&#34;744&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot overlooking my entire PureRef board. Lots of game screenshots, IRL photographs, concepts 2D artworks, 3D art and more is seen as tiny thumbnails.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;130&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;313px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to ref boards, this one above I would rate as a relatively tiny. In most of my previous projects I&amp;rsquo;ve went through many more bundles of subjects and pictures and usually my boards expand much more than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think in the creation of this scene I&amp;rsquo;ve been more controlled on the scope of the pieces I want to capture and create. As such that is also reflected in my ref board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing to mention is that in the board above in some spots there are screenshots from the project itself. I like to screen cap where I am and put it right next to the reference in order to compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-goals&#34;&gt;Initial Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets zoom in on some parts of the board above and see things further in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to tell you about the artists that inspired me and credit them properly in here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t personally know any of them but their work is brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos010.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1538&#34;
	height=&#34;1097&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;PureRef screenshot. To the left is a sculpt of a pillar with intricate gold motives. Work by Musaab Shukri. To the right are concept sculpts and pieces depicting fantasy deities and creatures. Work by Zak Foreman.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;140&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;336px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before getting into this current ritual project I had spent a long while in another block out I was creating in Unreal Engine 5. It was the test scene where I transitioned from UE4 to UE5 and learned the intricacies of UE5s Nanite and Lumen. That project itself was in an &amp;ldquo;Early Preview&amp;rdquo; build of UE5 and had lots of issues and crashes. I never uploaded any screenshots from it, but at some point I might revisit it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I got my hands on Early UE5, official demos such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/blog/a-first-look-at-unreal-engine-5&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Lumen in the Land of Nanite&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, then later &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.epicgames.com/site/en-US/news/unreal-engine-5-early-access-available-now&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Valley of the Ancient&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/blog/introducing-the-matrix-awakens-an-unreal-engine-5-experience&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;City Sample (The Matrix Awakens: An Unreal ENgine 5 Experience)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; released. After reading official docs about Nanite and seeing the sculpts and works in those demos I put a goal for my project. That was to try and create sculpts that are as dense and details as some of the assets seen in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I came across the artworks in the image above. The left image, for example, is a sculpt by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/artwork/kDyQ0A&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Musaab Shukri&lt;/a&gt; done exactly for the UE5 demo &amp;ldquo;Valley of the Ancient&amp;rdquo;. Work for Epic Games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images to the right are concepts by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/artwork/VgbLzN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zak Foreman&lt;/a&gt;. Those are again for the same demos. It depicts the visual fidelity and detail richness that Nanite could pull off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having realized these will be my visual fidelity goals, I set forward to find some real life photographs again. Some real spaces to get inspired from even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-diwan-i-khas-india&#34;&gt;The Diwan-i-Khas (India)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Diwan-i-Khas (Red Fort), or Hall of Private Audiences is a location in India that I found lots of inspiration in. It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to see the resemblance in the intricate carvings here when compared to the previous UE5 demos artworks we saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos011.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1666&#34;
	height=&#34;1052&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Reference board screenshot consisting of photographs from Hall of Private Audience, Fatehpur Sikri, Uttar Pradesh, India. Images depict red stoneworks carvings that loop into intricate patterns and snake like elements. There is also a photo from - &amp;ldquo;Interior of Hodha Bai&amp;rsquo;s Palace, Fatehpur Sikri&amp;rdquo;.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;158&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;380px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the very early blockouts I had, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really plan to head towards red stone look like the above. I still thought that the carvings are amazing reference for the sculpts I had yet to create. Also for any texture work that would go on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;circular-rooms&#34;&gt;Circular Rooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also pinned on my board some old, random photos of different circular rooms. I wanted a radial room after all, so I knew I should look at some from the get go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos012.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1389&#34;
	height=&#34;963&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Six photos put next to one another. The seventh is a game screenshot from &amp;ldquo;Shadow of the Colossus&amp;rdquo;. The others feature baroque and other architectural styles of circular rooms. Most have an opening in the ceiling that hosts set of windows that leak light in. Another photo is of a cave with god rays coming from open ceiling.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;144&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;346px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking at different spaces that have above light leaking in and creating nice god rays. When showing my very early blockouts to some friends, they all mentioned &amp;ldquo;Shadow of the Colossus&amp;rdquo; as a game that has very impressive interior shots with lighting just like that one. I&amp;rsquo;ve not played the game myself yet, but I knew I had to put those nice screenshots from it on my moodboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;star-wars-jedi-fallen-order&#34;&gt;Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m creating a project I always have immediate influence from the games I am playing at the time. In this case I was playing through Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order when creating parts of this environment. These screenshots from the game came into the board relatively late. Yet they (and the game) had a big influence on some of the decision making I took. It also helped me solve some visual issues I had and introduce more details like crack decals on the walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos013.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1461&#34;
	height=&#34;1108&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Lots of Fallen Order screenshots put into one place. Top left shows greenery, canopies and tree barks. Right is plaster walls. Below are ritual spaces with golden motives and lots of stalagmites and moist texturing.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;131&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;316px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I particularly looked at this section of the images, seen below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos014.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1717&#34;
	height=&#34;1074&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Lime-like green but in lots of parts cold gray cave walls. Old, sci-fi star wars structures with golden trims. Stalagmites that climb up in a fantastical, mushrooms-like way.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;159&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;383px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at the decal work and base texturing here and found lots of inspiration. Later on I needed more props to populated my empty spaces with, and after being inspired by Jedi I created ground dirt scatter piece as well as a set of pots - some intact, some smashed into pieces. I will showcase these later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;collaborators&#34;&gt;Collaborators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later through the project I had the pleasure to be inspired and helped by few more artists. Those are some of my friends and their influence here was direct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hayleyrumbold.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hayley Rumbold&lt;/a&gt; joined me in the creation of this project as a collaborator and a Cinematic Artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://oliverharbour.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Oliver Harbour&lt;/a&gt; did concept paint overs + few original pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SophieDesArt&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Sophie Deschamps&lt;/a&gt; gave me feedback a long the way and did a paint over as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/philcockburn&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Phil Cockburn&lt;/a&gt; left me lots and lots of tips and feedback through it all too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to mention them now though I will show you the works they created and the amazing influence they had in more detail inside the next blog entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-assets&#34;&gt;Initial Assets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having seen most of the reference images, we could step back now and see some of the first blockout shapes I made in Blender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos015.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1405&#34;
	height=&#34;1008&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Blender screenshot. Shows eight initial blockout assets. Includes architectural pieces like pillar, flat wall, wall with a circular window cut, ceiling dome pieces.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;139&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;334px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos016.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1168&#34;
	height=&#34;935&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Image of the same pieces seen above but now at an angle, in perspective, instead of a frontal, orthographic view like before.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;124&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;299px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the pieces I initially made and blocked out the scene. Some artists use Zbrush to block out pieces like that. I prefer to make these using a subdivision workflow, directly in Blender. I start by extruding a cube around and then beveling it in such a way that when I apply a Catmull-Clark subdivision on top, I get smooth, but not overly smooth shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make an absolute mess of the geometry. In some cases I insert lots of ngons (not seen in many obvious places here, but I still do). When using Catmull-Clark I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about my geometry flow mainly because I know the algorithm will make all of it into quads by the end when applied. If those quads follow awful edge loops, I frankly don&amp;rsquo;t mind. I don&amp;rsquo;t because I know that what I am making is then directly going into Zbrush. Once in there I will Dynamesh to get my to a density of geometry I like. When I do that any bad edge loops and flows gets retopologized to something much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos019.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1097&#34;
	height=&#34;872&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Wireframe view of one of the pieces seen above. Zoomed in, the image shows the edge loops and topology.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;125&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;301px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a resulting topology (image above). One that actually is pretty clean compared to some of the descriptions I wrote above, that happen most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the walls I later duplicated a few times in Blender:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos017.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;933&#34;
	height=&#34;1029&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Blender screenshot showing four copies of a flat wall, one above the other. Three are identical, ready to be customized in Zbrush, while the top one has a circular window cut instead.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;90&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;217px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To then as described above take into Zbrush:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos018.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1865&#34;
	height=&#34;1406&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The four pieces seen in the image above, now inspected in Zbrush. They are sculpted and each has unique cracks and damages, while one remains mostly intact.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;132&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;318px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where I refined my geometry, made topology that can hold good brush stokes and then detailed on top to get me to more finalized assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this all is an exercise in Nanite, I was not scared to be dense in topology and detail. I tried to make silhouettes rich in detail where the cracks and damages are. In some of the other wall pieces, I stamped stencil details in the form of writings, symbols and ritualistic stone carvings. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to rely on baking those down onto a lower poly, but instead use Decimation Master in Zbrush to get me to a lower dense poly, suitable for Nanite (as in being 150-200k tris. Even though Nanite could totally handle keeping some of the sculpts at 2-3m tris, it proved to be pointless and not add much detail).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;platform-sculpts&#34;&gt;Platform Sculpts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos020.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1519&#34;
	height=&#34;844&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Three props seen in a Blender screenshot. First one is a large, circular platform. Second is a pie cut modular piece. Third one is a bent wall.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;179&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;431px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My platform in the very center of the middle, I kept as one big shape. That is the first prop seen in the Blender screenshots above. Keeping it one big shape might sound a bit insane because it might be incredibly hard to keep high texel density even on 4k textures. That&amp;rsquo;s given how large the entire piece is. As such I briefly considered making a pie cut 1/4 of it, to then rotate by copying 3 more times and getting me the entire circle. I decided against that mainly for one reason: I knew I will create a dense Nanite mesh. As such I knew that most of my detail will sit in the geometry itself. If on top a slightly lower density albedo texture went, I decided it would not be a problem. Sculpting details on a platform this large on top, would also be quite fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the outer ring platform that wraps around that same platform, I decided to use the &amp;ldquo;pie cut&amp;rdquo; approach. I did that mainly because with its radius going further out the main platform, its cover area increased. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t scared of the texel density (though at that point I should have been) but more of the chore that sculpting such a giant piece would turn into, if I were to keep the entire ring a unique prop, instead of a pie cut. As such I made it into a &amp;ldquo;modular&amp;rdquo; cut and duplicated it many times in the scene, rotating it about, building up the rooms floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos021.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2178&#34;
	height=&#34;964&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Zbrush red matcap screenshot showing the circular platform now sculpted on top. It has brick-like details but also lots of swirling circle motives that give it a sci-fi, alien look.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;225&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;542px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above image was the first sculpt I did on the platform right after I took it into Zbrush. Going back to that talk about &amp;ldquo;familiar vs novel&amp;rdquo; right at the start of this blog, with this sculpt I later started to worry that the swirling, circular motives looked too alien. They are nice in an &amp;ldquo;alien crop circles&amp;rdquo; kind of way. But are they perhaps too abstract for this scene? Making everything look too smooth, too fudged and &lt;em&gt;non-concrete&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos022.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1520&#34;
	height=&#34;850&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Substance Painter screenshot. Shows the same platform as above, but now the sculpt is different and has more &amp;ldquo;brick&amp;rdquo; appearance. To the right is the UV view. All of the brick details are actual geometry as this is a Nanite mesh and I wanted to keep it more dense.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;429px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such I went back and sculpted it once more. This time around keeping a certain array of circles towards the middle, but in the outer parts giving a more structured, brick appearance. Seen in the image above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scene-shots&#34;&gt;Scene Shots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the platform in the context of the scene:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos023.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3162&#34;
	height=&#34;1779&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal 5 screenshot showing the middle platform. It has a cut in the middle that has a basin full of darkness and starry-looking texture. Little, untextured bridges at the sides lead to the outer platform radius.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is the old version. Below is the new one. I also put in some scene lights recolors and texture recolors to give everything a more controlled and realistic appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos024.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Another Unreal 5 screenshot. Camera angle is the same as above but now the platform sculpt is more refined. The little bridges are textured. The lighting in the scene is less orange and red.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoomed in towards the middle, we can inspect the platform and the &amp;ldquo;darkness basin&amp;rdquo; in the middle too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos025.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1007&#34;
	height=&#34;1050&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The middle platform and the basic cut in the middle, seen through a zoomed in camera.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;95&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;230px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the gaps of the bricks I put in flat planes. On those I added a liquid metal texture. At some point I was imagining the idea of cutting little canals going from the middle basin towards the outsides of the platform. In those canals liquid full of white stars would flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought its an interesting idea but I later abandoned it as I was worried that after introducing some other details on the outskirts of the scene, having black and white, high contrast, liquid in the cracks of the platforms proved to introduce visual clutter. It was making the scene fall a part more than it was tying it together or the novelty of the idea was worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next blog post we will look at the upper parts of the scene. We will inspect all of the wall and dome pieces seen in the Blender screenshots above which I used to create the higher parts of the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also revamped the pillars, just the way I reworked the middle platform above. I gave them more structure, carved runes and interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed seeing all of this,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Orbital Gateway - 10 - Recolored, Depth Fade, Stencils</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-010/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-010/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-010/orbital010.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Orbital Gateway - 10 - Recolored, Depth Fade, Stencils" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;recolor&#34;&gt;Recolor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick update with some recoloring and some other details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-010/orbital010.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Main camera angle. Compared to the previous post this time around the atmosphere and the color in the air are revamped. Most of the colors are in blue and teal, blue, green-ish ting. The only other color is of gold and yellow lights dotted around.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original concept had blue tint while my vision of it so far was mostly warm gray. (If you would like a reminder of how the original concept looks, you can find it in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-001/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;blog one of the series&lt;/a&gt;). I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to follow the concept word for word, but I could not stop but feel I might be missing out by not trying the colors in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such after some experimentation I landed on the colors you see above. I liked those quite a bit more than the original warm tomes I had going on. I then went into trying to clean up the portal / event horizon VFX even more. The previous one was too emissive and noisy for my liking and I though it was too busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is another angle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-010/peter-dimitrov-Screenshot00227.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Side angle showcasing the cylinder device in a spot where the right portal is on but the left one is malfunctioning and off. On the left one, that was in red lights last time, we now see a tint towards white and yellow lighting.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also see I cut out the concept of the red, warning like colors. I still want to convey the idea of the gate being partially broken and malfunctioning, but maybe going for red and alarming colors was too obvious and easy. Sure it worked out but I think there are more creative ways to do it, I just have to find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gamut-analysis&#34;&gt;Gamut Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-010/color-gamut-peter-dimitrov-cap073.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1524&#34;
	height=&#34;528&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Two screenshots. Left is the old view of the scene, with red lights. The right side is the new view, with more yellow and blue lights. Next to each of those screenshot is a gamut look analysis, breaking down the colors and showing them onto a circular color selection with the colors used highlighted. When looking at the version with mostly yellow and blues, the color selection is clearly much more controlled and limited.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;288&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;692px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gamut is much more limited in colors now and I think the end result is quite more harmonic composition wise. You can see a reading of it in the picture above.
I added some cut and exposed wires but I have yet to try adding some sparks and other animated VFX. That might help sell the malfunctioning concept without the use of the red color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;baking-normal-details&#34;&gt;Baking Normal Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I went into making some more pipes for the background. I also made a depth fade shader that gives a force field like effect where some of the pipes go through. Then I went into creating some hard surface stencils and baked details to use and stamp in Substance Painter. I modeled them in Maya and then baked normals of them in Substance Designer. I took those normals to use in Painter. I have just a few going on now but I&amp;rsquo;m going to make more in order to cover some of the otherwise empty areas on the panel surfaces of the portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see it below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-010/peter-dimitrov-progress-img002.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Few screenshots overlaid in one picture. To the left: 3D viewport shot from Maya. Shows 3D, highpoly, hardsurface details. In the middle: those same 3D pieces loaded into Substance Designer and baked onto flat planes, producing 2D textures. To the right: the baked normal details used on some of the geometries in the scene.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gif-progression&#34;&gt;Gif Progression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a GIF of my dances with colors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-010/peter-dimitrov-progress-gif-space-008-compressed.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;974&#34;
	height=&#34;548&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Gif cut showing a timelapse of the changes and progress in color in the scene. Starts from dark, warm grays and reds and ends up to brighter, cold grays, yellows and blues.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-011/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Orbital Gateway - 06 - Metals and Textures</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-006/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-006/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-006/orbital006.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Orbital Gateway - 06 - Metals and Textures" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;texturing&#34;&gt;Texturing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone. Quick update with a latest preview of how the scene is going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dived into UV mapping and some materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-006/orbital006.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Main UE4 camera shot, showing the portal cylinder. Material and texture work can be seen, with the greebles now having metallic shine while cables appear rubber and blue and there are some golden trims scattered too.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half of the panels still don&amp;rsquo;t have textures. I went with silver/chromium look tied up with some gold and golden trims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;panels&#34;&gt;Panels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I managed to go through four of the panels and texture them. I laid them out on the same UV texture set so they share bitmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not completely happy with the detail, noises and colors on them, but I&amp;rsquo;m setting up everything with smart materials so I should be able to easily tweak all of them. I just need to UV map the rest tomorrow. Fun. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View of just the mapped panels plus the gate frame:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-006/peter-dimitrov-cap073.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1384&#34;
	height=&#34;902&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Substance Painter screenshot showing 4 panels and a cable asset bundle. View is Material to the left and AO to the right.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;153&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;368px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The background I started with a trim sheet so I can easily introduce some patterns later on. Though arguably it will need some geometry there too as to not be too flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gif-progress&#34;&gt;Gif progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Process gif:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-006/peter-dimitrov-progress-gif-space-005.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;974&#34;
	height=&#34;548&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Timelapse process gif showing the build up from placeholder, plastic looking materials to ones that now have metal shine and detail.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll need to work more in order to balance the amount of detail on each panel through their textures. I want some panels to have golden elements too but I am going slow in order not to overwhelm it. Also I want to map and texture to the existing level the other 5-6 panels and then I&amp;rsquo;ll start trying the same changes uniformly on all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to bake some normal stencils and decals that I will then stamp directly on some of the empty surfaces for some extra detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any comments are appreciated,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-007/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Neon Graveyard - 08 - Atmosphere</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/cover008.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Neon Graveyard - 08 - Atmosphere" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/cover008.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Main camera shot. The small hill with a cathedral in neon on top. The land now has a blue mist and the sky is filled with aggressive clouds.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you remember the scene from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-007/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;last time&lt;/a&gt;, you would probably notice that it looks completely different. That is, looking at the atmosphere, at least. The layout is more or less the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mist&#34;&gt;Mist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had this idea, of having mist just above the surface, since the very start. I purposely postponed it until now, though, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to get crazy with tweaking volumetric fog settings, alpha and fog cards and putting crazy amount of time in it, whilst not having the basic layout figured out or any of the props ready. But now, when nearly all of the props are ready, I had the time to sit down and work on vapor and smog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone wanting to recreate this, the ground mist is just a very large &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particle Emitter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Its tied up to a &lt;em&gt;Clouds texture&lt;/em&gt;, pans a tiny bit, has a pretty short lifespan and is spawn cylindrical. After that its just a matter of tweaking your &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volumetric Fog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; settings in your &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exponential Height Fog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; volume. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the guy in Epics &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xd7-rTzfmCo&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;video&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(14th minute mark)&lt;/em&gt; about Volumetric Fog in the Engine quickly recreates something very similar. The only part I added myself, is how I placed it in the world. It&amp;rsquo;s just below the surface of my Landscape. And that&amp;rsquo;s how I made it look like ground mist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/other_shot_neon_peter_dimitrov15.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The cathedral seen from an angle closer to the ground. This makes the mist floating above ground more obvious.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stained-glass&#34;&gt;Stained Glass&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another, very important addition since last time, is the Stained Glass material that I created. It&amp;rsquo;s made from scratct in Substance Designer. What you see here is version 2.0, as the first one I created, I abandoned after a bit, as I though its shape was too simple. It had a diamond pattern going for it, and I wanted something more intricate looking than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/other_shot_neon_peter_dimitrov16.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Angled, closer shot of the cathedral. The tower and the right wing of it have a strong, mostly purple stained glass in intricate hues and patterns.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main approach to it was creating a base pattern and then picking up different areas of it and applying a few individual &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flood Fills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Each Flood Fill is turned to Color and then the hue, saturation and lightness of each shape that the Fill has picked up is randomised. The tricky part was giving it a shining look afterwards, in the Engine. If you look at just the material &amp;ldquo;ball&amp;rdquo; in Substance, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like much on its own. To give it that emissive look, I masked just a small portion of the whole patter. I applied another Flood Fill (by now third) and gave it sharp, stained masked noise with a Slope Blur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/other_shot_neon_peter_dimitrov17.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Close up shot of the stained glass. Circular motives that overlap into one another. Each different circle is colored in a different hue, raging from a lime, dark, cold green to an electric but warm red.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m particularly happy with this approach, and it gave me one thing I didn&amp;rsquo;t anticipate and wasn&amp;rsquo;t aiming to achieve. If you look at the texture up close in Unreal (the screenshot above), the emission mask is distinct and clear (white magenta bits). As you start going further away from it, though, the Engine shrinks the texture quality a bit, which blurs the emissive pixels. Those pixels then, start to work together with the Bloom settings of the scene, and fill the whole glass surface with a dark, electric, blue color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/28_peter_dimitrov_neon_gravestones.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1452&#34;
	height=&#34;855&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot from Substance Designer showing node set up that creates the above described colored circles for the stained glass. The screenshot is focused on &amp;ldquo;Flood Fill&amp;rdquo; nodes.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;169&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;407px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(As I described, you can feed an outline of your pattern towards a Flood Fill. You can then use a Flood Fill To Color to randomise the HSL of each generated shape. You can see all of that in the screenshot above.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are making a strained texture of your own, I would suggest experimenting with emissive mask, but also pay attention to your Bloom settings in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post Processing Volume&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. A good combination of both, always makes for exciting results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the pattern of the texture, I was in parts inspired by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/blogs/steppenwolf/306A/substance-designer-random-things-3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Matthias Schmidt&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; techniques, which he shares over in his blog. Check that out too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-things&#34;&gt;Other Things&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/other_shot_neon_peter_dimitrov18.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Angled look at the mausoleums and the mist inside their doors. The doors gaps are now not empty but have a shiny metal wrought panels.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most things are ready by now. I still have a few objects to put textures to. The boxes that you can still see are placeholder for hopefully some statues of something looking like a weeping angel. I want one or two of those, to contrast the very straight shapes of the rest of the headstones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also still working on the details of the main gate that you can see in the very first shot in this post. Facade details around the big window too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making this project has been quite a fun journey. I think this will be my last post about it though. As long as it goes about approach explanation at least. My next one &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;hopefully&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; will be a gallery to showcase the final result. I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on the video, to showcase the casket as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/other_shot_neon_peter_dimitrov04.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The cyberpunk casket, seen from an angle. Showcases mainly the ventilators and the server racks with their blue and green lights.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Casket as seen from a few posts ago, as I have a feeling some of you probably don&amp;rsquo;t even remember it. It&amp;rsquo;s still here! Going to animate it for a final video.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I started this project a few months ago, is my university. As such I&amp;rsquo;ll be submitting it as a thesis in about a week now. So that&amp;rsquo;s the deadline by which you will hopefully see the final result as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;progress-gif&#34;&gt;Progress GIF&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-008/gif_neon_03_peter_dimitrov%28compressed%29.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1274&#34;
	height=&#34;717&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Main camera angle but this time around seen in a GIF. Progression can be seen in the lighting, the fog and the sky that goes from a blank gradient to detailed clouds.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Some of you know I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of progress GIFs, so here is a very compressed final one.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To those of you who you stuck with me through the whole journey, and read all of the previous entries (about eight), I want to say thanks. I hope you found them useful and intriguing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pete.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/neon-graveyard-009/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
