<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Blender on Pete Dimitrov&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/tags/blender/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Blender on Pete Dimitrov&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://petedimitrovart.com/tags/blender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Amarantos Ritual - 03 - Roots and Nanite Sculpts</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos025-c.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Amarantos Ritual - 03 - Roots and Nanite Sculpts" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;walls-of-the-circular-room&#34;&gt;Walls of the Circular Room&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the previous blog entry we looked in detail at the center platform and its sculpt. I showed how the mesh underwent a few changes, getting it from alien crop circles appearance to a more ordinary brick and pavement look. You could revisit those screenshots over here - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;The Amarantos Ritual - 02 - Reference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did, however, slightly skip over looking at the lower walls of the environment and what I did with their sculpts. I also mentioned that we should look at the upper parts of the scene too, and briefly talk about the wall pieces, windows, and dome elements there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos025.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Lower ground camera screenshot that is pointed towards the upwards parts of the scene. It reveals the orb floating in the middle of the scene, bathed in light (in the shape of alpha card God Rays). Above the orb one can see the circumference of the initial lower room shrink inwards. On the walls of that are windows cut in the form of circles. On the very top, the ceiling is dome shaped. It opens up like a flower flooding further with daylight the otherwise dark interior. Unreal Engine 5 screenshot.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;roof-blockout&#34;&gt;Roof Blockout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a step back, in this screenshot seen below we can see my initial blockout of the ceiling. My approach to putting the place together was as follows: I blocked out the lower levels walls. I put in the middle platform so the orb is centered, floating on it. I added little bridges and a bunch of pillars. I then added one upper level of walls - the ones where the circumference of the room shrinks once for the first time. It creates a dome like appearance where the pillars are. The walls above get to host some circle cut windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I had all of this blocked out, I set on to sculpt further all of the above described assets. After sculpting them I did an initial texturing pass. Even then, when I still had no roof, I knew I want to create a dome appearance on the upper ceilings. I knew I want to open up a tall space around there and not end up the celling ending close to the orb, thus making a claustrophobic space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I knew and was planning all of that I had still not made most of the blockout upper assets and ceiling pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead once I had done the first sculpting and texturing pass of the lower levels, and once I had seen it work well and I liked it, I set off to continue the missing ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos026.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1248&#34;
	height=&#34;1071&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Image crop looking at the upper parts of the scene. Shows the dome ceiling building up few levels of shapes and silhouettes. The top one is the most intricate one, with flower and fractal elements. All of the upper parts have placeholder, gray, materials while the lower parts are textured. UE5 image.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;116&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;279px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is how the upper levels looked - in mid-blockout - when I was testing out the shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only were I testing out the visual and silhouette of the shapes themselves but I also was engaged fully into looking at something else too: their use with light. I wanted to create interesting patterns at the very top that then would flood the lower parts of the environment in light that leaves spellbinding, exciting shadow silhouettes. Here light itself was my main attention and my main &amp;ldquo;asset&amp;rdquo;. It dictated what was going to happen with the sculpture pieces. Light inspired me in the making of the flower-like opening on the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos027.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2115&#34;
	height=&#34;900&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Zbrush screenshot. Two images put next to one another. To the left is a view of a pillar, damaged and turned into three different assets. To the right is a ceiling dome, modular piece. It has protrusions for detail but also a large damage crack.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;235&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;564px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having figured what pieces work and what pieces I like from the initial Blender blockouts, I set off to take some of them inside Zbrush. The modular building pieces that I liked I retopologized in Zbrush using Dynamesh. I then further sculpted and polished details on top. Some I duplicated multiple times and shattered in different ways, deriving me extra dressings and details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos028.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1415&#34;
	height=&#34;976&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Lower, orthographic camera view of upper dome ceiling assets. Top parts has a fractal-like appearance. Lower dome bent has a crack and damage in one version, while the other (to the right) is intact. The images were taken inside Zbrush.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;144&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;347px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a final step inside Zbrush I used Decimation Master in order to lower the polycount of each sculpt. I had most pieces sitting at 2-3 million tris. Nanite could handle that but it would result with each mesh being around 200-300 MBs, maybe even more. I found that would be needless given that this high density of poly was not exactly looking more detailed than a well decimated version that would be 100-200k tris (instead of 2-3m). The file sizes of those would be much more manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to remember that we need to UV map these too. UV Mapping a 3m triangles sculpt would be much more taxing on Blender (and on us) than a 300k tris one, which would be a trivial task to uv map if one has a polished, good geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;door-asset&#34;&gt;Door Asset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above described process I used for the creation of the front door as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos029.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;790&#34;
	height=&#34;920&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Initial blockout of some of the shapes of the door. Screenshot from Blender. Shows a square plate wall. It has a circle cut in the middle. There, a carving shape sits. It has appearance like the Zerg logo from Starcraft.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;85&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;206px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a quick shape exploration in Blender before moving anything into Zbrush. I played with an array modifier with rotations in order to try and get some interesting shape. Here I once again thought at light as my main asset, as such I wanted to create some silhouette that once lit would aggressively cast some interesting shadows in the middle of the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos030.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;955&#34;
	height=&#34;1040&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Another Blender screenshot. Looks at the door pieces bit further away from. The wall plate and circle cut are now more defined. The shape in the middle is more of a spiral instead of the previous inverted Zerg shape.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;91&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;220px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The walls to the left and the right were shapes just for placeholder as I knew I would use the existing modular walls in the project instead of making brand new ones unique to the corridor of this door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos031.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1579&#34;
	height=&#34;1030&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Blender screenshot where the screen is split into two. To the left is a UV Layout screen. To the right is Modelling Layout screen. On the left is seen the result of a UVPackmaster3 Addon, showing uv shells overlaid on an uv quadrant.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;153&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;367px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was slight difference in the process of making this door, when compared to the walls we looked at before. In here, I UV mapped my initial pieces and then in Zbrush used non-destructive approach both to the sculpting and the decimation of the topology by the end. That way I preserved my UV maps and didn&amp;rsquo;t have to re-map once the sculpts were ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the same approach I used for the circular platform in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos032.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1505&#34;
	height=&#34;1000&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Zbrush screenshot showing the door. The sculpt here is now rich in detail and relief carvings on the surface. Image to the left shows the door at a slight angle, while the image on the right shows it from the very front, in orthographic view.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;361px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is a detailed look at my sculpt pass on the door. I&amp;rsquo;ve not included the spiral shape as I thought its not necessary to run a sculpting pass on it - instead it could be ordinary Nanite mesh with just a tiling material on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos033.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1307&#34;
	height=&#34;792&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Substance Painter screenshot. Viewport is divided into two. Left side is the door seen in perspective. Right side is the UV space showing all of its shells. On both sides we can observe the &amp;ldquo;Thickness&amp;rdquo; bake applied.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;165&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;396px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the sculpt was done I decimated the asset while preserving UVs. I went into Substance Painter where I baked my maps and set off to texture. In the image above the UVs differ slightly compared to the Blender shots before. That&amp;rsquo;s mainly because I did some extra polish before taking it outside of Blender and into Zbrush. With that I utilized my UV space better to not have the empty space seen in the first Blender UV screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos034.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;699&#34;
	height=&#34;856&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The door seen fully textured but lit slightly in a flat way. It is previewed once again in Substance Painter. The base material is stone matching the texturing of all other assets. On top sits green algae like texture that is masked with AO but also hand painted in lots of places too.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;81&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;195px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;god-rays-alpha-cards&#34;&gt;God Rays Alpha Cards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the ceiling and the dome appearance was created I put in some god rays and atmospheric 2D alpha cards. Those face the camera at most of the times and if you wanted similar ones you could dig out materials and blueprints set ups from Epic over here - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.unrealengine.com/marketplace/en-US/product/blueprints&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Blueprints - Legacy UE4 Sample Project&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is UE4 and its marked as Legacy in some spots, but the Blueprint set up (and materials) found in there for &amp;ldquo;God Rays&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Fog Cards&amp;rdquo; are set up incredibly well. Their design and function stands perfect even when migrated in UE5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos035.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1387&#34;
	height=&#34;629&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal Marketplace screenshot. Shows the &amp;ldquo;Blueprints&amp;rdquo; sample project. The screenshot from the project seen above has a butterfly in the middle. If inspected closely, one can notice a long, bright god ray alpha card behind it. That is the ones we are after.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;220&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;529px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;roots&#34;&gt;Roots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the alpha card rays implemented and my attention came back entirely on the lower parts of the scene. Where all of the &amp;ldquo;action&amp;rdquo; would take place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at it and could see that it was sitting predominantly empty. No detail props or set dressings. Even the walls met the floors at a perfect 90 degrees angle which took away from the natural look of the space and made for an artificial CG look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to remedy that. As such I looked into making bundles of props I could scatter around and about. Pottery, ground dirt pile, smashed pieces of pots. Stone tablets with inscriptions or symbols on them. Fallen parts of the upper ceiling pillars, now sitting on the dusty floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet my walls remained empty. Overly simple. The upper parts of the environment had cracks and tons of damages on the walls, spilling in even further light and using that as a detailing asset. But the lower ones? They were mostly intact. Empty. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to dig out any holes there because the camera would be seeing straight out of them. That would break immersion, because, as you could guess, the exterior scene is completely empty. As such that idea was a no go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is when I started thinking about roots. What if oversized, magical, incredibly wide roots were spiraling around like snakes? They could populate the walls better and reach towards the middle of the room, towards the floating orb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pitched that idea out loud to my friend Sophie Deschamps. She loved the idea so much, and being the cool artist she is, without me even asking, took the screenshot I had just sent her and painted over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She got me this artwork:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos036.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1345&#34;
	height=&#34;773&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The environment captured from one of the usual camera angles seen before. On top is a concept paint over by hand. It consists of immense, magnificent roots crawling out of the window gaps and reaching towards the orb in the middle. Once a root reaches the middle, its width becomes smaller and it changes color into bright greens and blues. In the middle part the roots start to wiggle upwards, as if trying to reach and touch the orb in the middle of the scene. The orb is colored in an overpowering blue aura.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;173&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;417px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing this concept paint over, I knew immediately. I knew that indeed this is the next move and as such I set of to making some roots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could not describe how helpful and inspiring this paint over was, as such, thank you, Sophie!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blueprints-for-the-roots&#34;&gt;Blueprints for the Roots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My process behind making the roots was at first in big chunk in UE5 itself. The space is already blocked out and I wanted to have a direct and immediate way to &amp;ldquo;crawl&amp;rdquo; around different roots and see their influence and shape on the environment. As such I used a spline system Blueprint directly in UE5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could have opened Blender and positioned my floor and walls in the configuration I have in the scene. That would be a trivial and not very time consuming task as I already have all of my measurements set. Its just a matter of moving them from one place to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet I dislike jumping in and out of Unreal. I like doing as much as I could in the engine itself as that then keeps my art process with less friction. Frictionless means more creativity and energy spend towards whatever I am creating and not the dialogue that I have between the different software packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7YUxM0NDWRY&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Youtube embedded video above, showcasing a tutorial titled &amp;ldquo;UE4 Tutorial: Add spline-meshes procedurally&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know the YouTuber but this video, even though old, is very useful.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Video above is UE4 but things seen in it should work well in UE5 too. If some parts are hard to follow, I suggest giving a go to this one instead - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eKIiWa19EMI&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Unreal Engine 4 Tutorial - Splines - Spline Meshes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. I remember using that at one point or another as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not wanting to move between modelling packages, as mentioned already, I imported in UE5 a Blueprint system I had made years prior. It&amp;rsquo;s one that I had started for some random UE4 project I could not even remember now &lt;em&gt;(tutorials for making similar blueprint are seen in the videos above)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time I had carried it into my Orbital Gateway, (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/orbital-gateway-013/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;found here&lt;/a&gt;) where I had used it to scatter in line all of the metal platforms. It was also used to shape all of the big, vacuum like cables that are the kernel of the vision of that project. In that Gateway environment I had implemented some improvements into my initial spline Blueprint too. Things like being able to per instance basis pick different static mesh and different material to go onto the spline. It was a solution battle tested and as such I wanted to reuse it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos037.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot of the very first moment I dragged around the tube splines blueprint. I started with very thin and subtle ones. In the middle is the orb floating in the room. To the left of it is a tube that looks like cable. It starts from the upper part of the picture and crawls down the walls and reaches the middle, where the orb is.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went in Blender and I made an initial tube that I kept higher in poly than I usually do (as in with extra edge loops). Using Unreal 5 now, unlike back in my previous projects that were Unreal 4, here I could afford higher polycount with the knowledge that all of my blocked out pieces will end up being Nanite meshes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That tube I put into the spline Blueprint. Over the course of a few days I slowly build up bundles of large roots. Those were blockout so if any when taking a turn in the world were looked lowpoly, or any surface got distorted, it didn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I wanted to block them out directly in UE5 but I still had in mind exporting the resulted meshes back into Blender in order to polish the visual slightly and UV map them by the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos038.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Same angle as before - the orb floats in the middle. Now both to the left, where there were thin cables, but also in the middle of the picture and close to the camera, are tubes that are much more thick and actually look like roots. They branch out in smaller and smaller slithering shapes. Image taken in Unreal 5.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos039.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Lower ground level camera. Below the floating orb in the middle, bathed in alpha cards light, there are the roots blockouts. Those slither around on the ground and once reaching the middle of the platform start to move upwards, as if trying to touch the orb.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good to mention that I&amp;rsquo;ve not implemented control over the thickness of my splines on per spline point basis. As such I could not select a middle point of a root and scale it up to give it thickness. Instead I exported my uniformly thick roots from Unreal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First step to do that was to Merge Actors by selecting the spline - opening &amp;ldquo;Merge Actors&amp;rdquo; from the Tools submenu - hitting &amp;ldquo;Merge Actors&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;(you can see that in the image below)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would ask me a location to save the spline as a static mesh under the Project Directory. I then navigate to it in the Content Browser, right click on its icon and go to - Asset Actions - Export. That allows me to save the resulting mesh outside of UE5 as an *.fbx. I open that in Blender and I do my thickness scale up polish, UV polish, and subdivision to make it even smoother Nanite mesh. I import that back into UE5 and I replace the original spline blueprints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos043.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1823&#34;
	height=&#34;1088&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal 5 editor screenshot, showing an action in 3 steps. First open Tools submenu and select Merge Actors. Second select your spline blueprint in the world (see in the middle of the image). Third, use the newly opened Merge Actors window to save out the splines into ordinary Static Mesh. I suggest doing this by the end of your projects even on splines you like the visual of, as keeping it to splines increases draw calls immensely and will drag performance down. Saving out to Static Mesh bakes it down to one draw call.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;167&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;402px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the paint over from Sophie the roots were incredibly large and impressive. I slowly build up mine to be large too. But I knew I will probably keep them smaller than her concept. I took that decision with the idea of keeping the focal point to be the orb. I thought that if I introduced roots that were very, very thick, they would draw viewers attention. Also I though that if indeed they were that big, I would need to figure out some set dressings and props to put on their surface, as to not leave them too bare, empty, boring and lacking detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;filling-up-the-empty-parts&#34;&gt;Filling up the Empty Parts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With those roots looked at, we could take one step back and see the build up of set dressings in one corner of the environment. That way you could get a better perception of how all of the described details and props added up to build up the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos040.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Image collage. To the left are two screenshots of a dirt lump seen in Zbrush. To the right is that same prop used in UE5. Showcases close up of the corners of the walls. Where wall meets floor, the dirt piles prop is used as set dressing.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image above shows a dirty looking Zbrush sculpt I made. It looks not that amazing in the Zbrush render, but once placed in the world with a tiling ground dirt material, to match the floors already there, it helped hide the 90 degrees I mentioned some time ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos041.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The close up from UE5 seen above. This time the pillars protruding from the bent walls are redone and have more square look. They also have intricate rune relieves on them. They are still flatly textured with placeholder materials.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then polished and revamped the pillars (image above). I wanted to give them better shape and texture. Something more realistic and intricate than the first draft. I also added pottery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/amarantos042.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Shot identical to above. The at first empty spaces are now filled with roots that slither in all directions. The roots now have textures of barks too. There are flower foliage assets that have blue blooms and light up the scene in a magical, eerie glow.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we can see the influence of the roots. I textured them using tiling materials from Megascans that I mixed in my own way using triplanar mapping in my UE5 shader. There is also a slight jump with me introducing some foliage and flower pods, but we will go into describing that process in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sophie Deschamps, who did the paint over seen in this entry, is a Level Artist at Ubisoft Montpellier. You can find and follow her work over at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SophieDesArt&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/sdess&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Artstation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post we saw the scene fill up with props, dressings and more detail. We looked at using Blueprints spline systems for blocking out roots directly in UE5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was, however more going on during, and immediately after everything seen above. It was experiment and struggle with color that persisted for a little while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attempted different color combinations where the roots flower blooms would light up the scene in blues, purples, reds, oranges. The orb would carry on that color in its fresnel too. Experimenting and switching between those colors went on for a while and then I got some ideas and help from another friend, just the way Sophie helped and inspired me with the roots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up we will look at that and how that influenced changing the orb in the middle for something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Amarantos Ritual - 02 - Reference</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos008-c.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Amarantos Ritual - 02 - Reference" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;novel-and-old-concepts&#34;&gt;Novel and Old Concepts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second entry of this series I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to explore my references and early inspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at lots of artists, games, and photographs from all kinds of places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start a new art idea its good to look at plenty of references. You can source your idea or inspiration by mixing together existing paintings, photos, short stories, books and more. It&amp;rsquo;s also integral to look at real life photos. We aim for believable and realistic spaces and layouts (or at least I do in this project). That is even when our subjects are fantastical. As such parts of what we are about to create needs to be grounded on reality. Those parts need to have roots in what is already familiar in the viewers eyes. Then on top you sprinkle bit of the eerie, unknown, novel and bizarre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-stage&#34;&gt;Current Stage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the previous blog (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;The Amarantos Ritual - 01 - Beginning&lt;/a&gt;) after figuring out my Houdini orb and that it will be the center piece of the composition and the layout, I was at this stage of the scene:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos007.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3162&#34;
	height=&#34;1779&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal 5 screenshot from the previous blog entry. A circular room with placeholder gray materials and strong orange glow. There is a fuzzy, liquid metal orb in the very middle. Around are pillars with ornate details on their tops. The walls have slight gaps for sci-fi-esque windows. There is a door that is slightly ajar and sunlight comes out of it.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did some further tweaks and added a little bridge platforms to connect the middle, circular platform to the outer edges of the room. In the very dead center, I cut a gap in order to place more &amp;ldquo;liquid metal&amp;rdquo; type of effect. I wanted to lead to the idea that perhaps in that basin in the middle of the room, there was an inactive substance. Few people, aliens, or some other creatures, enter the room and interact with that inactive substance. With their presence, it comes to life. It forms into the orb that then starts to float in the upper, middle point, space of the large room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you perhaps remember from the last entry, I really wanted to lead towards the idea of a ritual happening in this space. The creatures that enter the room bring the orb to life. They perhaps worship it, fear it, but are also astonished by it. Does it bring them energy? Food? Pleasure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the relationship between these characters and this &amp;ldquo;inanimate&amp;rdquo; object that the next moment seems to come to life and be lively?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I start new scenes, or any other type of art, I usually make up a few sentences that form a story. The moment I have that I start to ask questions. Those questions are very much like the ones above. They help me refine and see more than what there is at first in my mind. They help me make a 3D space that is more believable, interesting and rich in story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is an exercise I think you should try yourself. Whenever you create a layout, ask yourself why its the way it is? When you place props, ask yourself why they are there and what their relation to other objects around them is? Ask how you can tie up one item to another so they look more coherent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos008.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3162&#34;
	height=&#34;1779&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Another Unreal 5 screenshot. Camera angle is the same as the image above. This time the strong orange glow in the left parts of the circular room is removed. The gray, placeholder materials have a cooler tone in general as well. The liquid metal orb from Houdini still floats in the middle of the room, but the central platform is now connected by little bridges. There is a basin cut in the middle too, with darkness inside it.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into more screenshots inside this 3D space, lets take a step back. As mentioned in the start of this entry, I want to include my references and early influences behind the art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.pureref.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PureRef&lt;/a&gt; to put all of my reference images in one place. I like using this piece of software because it&amp;rsquo;s very lightweight. Some people use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://miro.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Miro&lt;/a&gt; which has a similar idea but more annotation tools, sticky notes and other cool features. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that PureRef is easier on the RAM than having a webpage open or using the Miro desktop software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my ref board I make sure to mix plenty of 2D art, 3D art but also real life photographs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos009.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;973&#34;
	height=&#34;744&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot overlooking my entire PureRef board. Lots of game screenshots, IRL photographs, concepts 2D artworks, 3D art and more is seen as tiny thumbnails.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;130&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;313px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to ref boards, this one above I would rate as a relatively tiny. In most of my previous projects I&amp;rsquo;ve went through many more bundles of subjects and pictures and usually my boards expand much more than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think in the creation of this scene I&amp;rsquo;ve been more controlled on the scope of the pieces I want to capture and create. As such that is also reflected in my ref board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing to mention is that in the board above in some spots there are screenshots from the project itself. I like to screen cap where I am and put it right next to the reference in order to compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-goals&#34;&gt;Initial Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets zoom in on some parts of the board above and see things further in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to tell you about the artists that inspired me and credit them properly in here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t personally know any of them but their work is brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos010.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1538&#34;
	height=&#34;1097&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;PureRef screenshot. To the left is a sculpt of a pillar with intricate gold motives. Work by Musaab Shukri. To the right are concept sculpts and pieces depicting fantasy deities and creatures. Work by Zak Foreman.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;140&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;336px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before getting into this current ritual project I had spent a long while in another block out I was creating in Unreal Engine 5. It was the test scene where I transitioned from UE4 to UE5 and learned the intricacies of UE5s Nanite and Lumen. That project itself was in an &amp;ldquo;Early Preview&amp;rdquo; build of UE5 and had lots of issues and crashes. I never uploaded any screenshots from it, but at some point I might revisit it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I got my hands on Early UE5, official demos such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/blog/a-first-look-at-unreal-engine-5&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Lumen in the Land of Nanite&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, then later &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.epicgames.com/site/en-US/news/unreal-engine-5-early-access-available-now&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Valley of the Ancient&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/blog/introducing-the-matrix-awakens-an-unreal-engine-5-experience&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;City Sample (The Matrix Awakens: An Unreal ENgine 5 Experience)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; released. After reading official docs about Nanite and seeing the sculpts and works in those demos I put a goal for my project. That was to try and create sculpts that are as dense and details as some of the assets seen in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I came across the artworks in the image above. The left image, for example, is a sculpt by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/artwork/kDyQ0A&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Musaab Shukri&lt;/a&gt; done exactly for the UE5 demo &amp;ldquo;Valley of the Ancient&amp;rdquo;. Work for Epic Games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images to the right are concepts by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/artwork/VgbLzN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zak Foreman&lt;/a&gt;. Those are again for the same demos. It depicts the visual fidelity and detail richness that Nanite could pull off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having realized these will be my visual fidelity goals, I set forward to find some real life photographs again. Some real spaces to get inspired from even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-diwan-i-khas-india&#34;&gt;The Diwan-i-Khas (India)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Diwan-i-Khas (Red Fort), or Hall of Private Audiences is a location in India that I found lots of inspiration in. It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to see the resemblance in the intricate carvings here when compared to the previous UE5 demos artworks we saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos011.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1666&#34;
	height=&#34;1052&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Reference board screenshot consisting of photographs from Hall of Private Audience, Fatehpur Sikri, Uttar Pradesh, India. Images depict red stoneworks carvings that loop into intricate patterns and snake like elements. There is also a photo from - &amp;ldquo;Interior of Hodha Bai&amp;rsquo;s Palace, Fatehpur Sikri&amp;rdquo;.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;158&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;380px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the very early blockouts I had, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really plan to head towards red stone look like the above. I still thought that the carvings are amazing reference for the sculpts I had yet to create. Also for any texture work that would go on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;circular-rooms&#34;&gt;Circular Rooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also pinned on my board some old, random photos of different circular rooms. I wanted a radial room after all, so I knew I should look at some from the get go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos012.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1389&#34;
	height=&#34;963&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Six photos put next to one another. The seventh is a game screenshot from &amp;ldquo;Shadow of the Colossus&amp;rdquo;. The others feature baroque and other architectural styles of circular rooms. Most have an opening in the ceiling that hosts set of windows that leak light in. Another photo is of a cave with god rays coming from open ceiling.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;144&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;346px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking at different spaces that have above light leaking in and creating nice god rays. When showing my very early blockouts to some friends, they all mentioned &amp;ldquo;Shadow of the Colossus&amp;rdquo; as a game that has very impressive interior shots with lighting just like that one. I&amp;rsquo;ve not played the game myself yet, but I knew I had to put those nice screenshots from it on my moodboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;star-wars-jedi-fallen-order&#34;&gt;Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m creating a project I always have immediate influence from the games I am playing at the time. In this case I was playing through Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order when creating parts of this environment. These screenshots from the game came into the board relatively late. Yet they (and the game) had a big influence on some of the decision making I took. It also helped me solve some visual issues I had and introduce more details like crack decals on the walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos013.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1461&#34;
	height=&#34;1108&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Lots of Fallen Order screenshots put into one place. Top left shows greenery, canopies and tree barks. Right is plaster walls. Below are ritual spaces with golden motives and lots of stalagmites and moist texturing.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;131&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;316px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I particularly looked at this section of the images, seen below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos014.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1717&#34;
	height=&#34;1074&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Lime-like green but in lots of parts cold gray cave walls. Old, sci-fi star wars structures with golden trims. Stalagmites that climb up in a fantastical, mushrooms-like way.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;159&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;383px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at the decal work and base texturing here and found lots of inspiration. Later on I needed more props to populated my empty spaces with, and after being inspired by Jedi I created ground dirt scatter piece as well as a set of pots - some intact, some smashed into pieces. I will showcase these later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;collaborators&#34;&gt;Collaborators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later through the project I had the pleasure to be inspired and helped by few more artists. Those are some of my friends and their influence here was direct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hayleyrumbold.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hayley Rumbold&lt;/a&gt; joined me in the creation of this project as a collaborator and a Cinematic Artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://oliverharbour.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Oliver Harbour&lt;/a&gt; did concept paint overs + few original pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SophieDesArt&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Sophie Deschamps&lt;/a&gt; gave me feedback a long the way and did a paint over as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/philcockburn&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Phil Cockburn&lt;/a&gt; left me lots and lots of tips and feedback through it all too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to mention them now though I will show you the works they created and the amazing influence they had in more detail inside the next blog entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-assets&#34;&gt;Initial Assets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having seen most of the reference images, we could step back now and see some of the first blockout shapes I made in Blender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos015.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1405&#34;
	height=&#34;1008&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Blender screenshot. Shows eight initial blockout assets. Includes architectural pieces like pillar, flat wall, wall with a circular window cut, ceiling dome pieces.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;139&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;334px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos016.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1168&#34;
	height=&#34;935&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Image of the same pieces seen above but now at an angle, in perspective, instead of a frontal, orthographic view like before.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;124&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;299px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the pieces I initially made and blocked out the scene. Some artists use Zbrush to block out pieces like that. I prefer to make these using a subdivision workflow, directly in Blender. I start by extruding a cube around and then beveling it in such a way that when I apply a Catmull-Clark subdivision on top, I get smooth, but not overly smooth shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make an absolute mess of the geometry. In some cases I insert lots of ngons (not seen in many obvious places here, but I still do). When using Catmull-Clark I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about my geometry flow mainly because I know the algorithm will make all of it into quads by the end when applied. If those quads follow awful edge loops, I frankly don&amp;rsquo;t mind. I don&amp;rsquo;t because I know that what I am making is then directly going into Zbrush. Once in there I will Dynamesh to get my to a density of geometry I like. When I do that any bad edge loops and flows gets retopologized to something much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos019.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1097&#34;
	height=&#34;872&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Wireframe view of one of the pieces seen above. Zoomed in, the image shows the edge loops and topology.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;125&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;301px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a resulting topology (image above). One that actually is pretty clean compared to some of the descriptions I wrote above, that happen most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the walls I later duplicated a few times in Blender:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos017.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;933&#34;
	height=&#34;1029&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Blender screenshot showing four copies of a flat wall, one above the other. Three are identical, ready to be customized in Zbrush, while the top one has a circular window cut instead.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;90&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;217px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To then as described above take into Zbrush:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos018.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1865&#34;
	height=&#34;1406&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The four pieces seen in the image above, now inspected in Zbrush. They are sculpted and each has unique cracks and damages, while one remains mostly intact.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;132&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;318px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where I refined my geometry, made topology that can hold good brush stokes and then detailed on top to get me to more finalized assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this all is an exercise in Nanite, I was not scared to be dense in topology and detail. I tried to make silhouettes rich in detail where the cracks and damages are. In some of the other wall pieces, I stamped stencil details in the form of writings, symbols and ritualistic stone carvings. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to rely on baking those down onto a lower poly, but instead use Decimation Master in Zbrush to get me to a lower dense poly, suitable for Nanite (as in being 150-200k tris. Even though Nanite could totally handle keeping some of the sculpts at 2-3m tris, it proved to be pointless and not add much detail).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;platform-sculpts&#34;&gt;Platform Sculpts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos020.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1519&#34;
	height=&#34;844&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Three props seen in a Blender screenshot. First one is a large, circular platform. Second is a pie cut modular piece. Third one is a bent wall.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;179&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;431px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My platform in the very center of the middle, I kept as one big shape. That is the first prop seen in the Blender screenshots above. Keeping it one big shape might sound a bit insane because it might be incredibly hard to keep high texel density even on 4k textures. That&amp;rsquo;s given how large the entire piece is. As such I briefly considered making a pie cut 1/4 of it, to then rotate by copying 3 more times and getting me the entire circle. I decided against that mainly for one reason: I knew I will create a dense Nanite mesh. As such I knew that most of my detail will sit in the geometry itself. If on top a slightly lower density albedo texture went, I decided it would not be a problem. Sculpting details on a platform this large on top, would also be quite fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the outer ring platform that wraps around that same platform, I decided to use the &amp;ldquo;pie cut&amp;rdquo; approach. I did that mainly because with its radius going further out the main platform, its cover area increased. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t scared of the texel density (though at that point I should have been) but more of the chore that sculpting such a giant piece would turn into, if I were to keep the entire ring a unique prop, instead of a pie cut. As such I made it into a &amp;ldquo;modular&amp;rdquo; cut and duplicated it many times in the scene, rotating it about, building up the rooms floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos021.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2178&#34;
	height=&#34;964&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Zbrush red matcap screenshot showing the circular platform now sculpted on top. It has brick-like details but also lots of swirling circle motives that give it a sci-fi, alien look.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;225&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;542px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above image was the first sculpt I did on the platform right after I took it into Zbrush. Going back to that talk about &amp;ldquo;familiar vs novel&amp;rdquo; right at the start of this blog, with this sculpt I later started to worry that the swirling, circular motives looked too alien. They are nice in an &amp;ldquo;alien crop circles&amp;rdquo; kind of way. But are they perhaps too abstract for this scene? Making everything look too smooth, too fudged and &lt;em&gt;non-concrete&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos022.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1520&#34;
	height=&#34;850&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Substance Painter screenshot. Shows the same platform as above, but now the sculpt is different and has more &amp;ldquo;brick&amp;rdquo; appearance. To the right is the UV view. All of the brick details are actual geometry as this is a Nanite mesh and I wanted to keep it more dense.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;429px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such I went back and sculpted it once more. This time around keeping a certain array of circles towards the middle, but in the outer parts giving a more structured, brick appearance. Seen in the image above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scene-shots&#34;&gt;Scene Shots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the platform in the context of the scene:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos023.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3162&#34;
	height=&#34;1779&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal 5 screenshot showing the middle platform. It has a cut in the middle that has a basin full of darkness and starry-looking texture. Little, untextured bridges at the sides lead to the outer platform radius.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is the old version. Below is the new one. I also put in some scene lights recolors and texture recolors to give everything a more controlled and realistic appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos024.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Another Unreal 5 screenshot. Camera angle is the same as above but now the platform sculpt is more refined. The little bridges are textured. The lighting in the scene is less orange and red.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoomed in towards the middle, we can inspect the platform and the &amp;ldquo;darkness basin&amp;rdquo; in the middle too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/amarantos025.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1007&#34;
	height=&#34;1050&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The middle platform and the basic cut in the middle, seen through a zoomed in camera.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;95&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;230px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the gaps of the bricks I put in flat planes. On those I added a liquid metal texture. At some point I was imagining the idea of cutting little canals going from the middle basin towards the outsides of the platform. In those canals liquid full of white stars would flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought its an interesting idea but I later abandoned it as I was worried that after introducing some other details on the outskirts of the scene, having black and white, high contrast, liquid in the cracks of the platforms proved to introduce visual clutter. It was making the scene fall a part more than it was tying it together or the novelty of the idea was worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next blog post we will look at the upper parts of the scene. We will inspect all of the wall and dome pieces seen in the Blender screenshots above which I used to create the higher parts of the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also revamped the pillars, just the way I reworked the middle platform above. I gave them more structure, carved runes and interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed seeing all of this,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-003/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Amarantos Ritual - 01 - Beginning</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/amarantos001c.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Amarantos Ritual - 01 - Beginning" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;Foreword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last nine months I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly developing my latest environment scene. It&amp;rsquo;s process documented both in writing and in work-in-progress images has been scattered across my social channels. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot of positive comments and encouragement a long the way by some wonderful people. Some of you, dear readers, might have even seen the project and the aforementioned images already. I wanted to still pull it all together, so to speak, into one condensed place. Tie up the scattered posts and ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that tie up, I hope for some of you to find inspiration. Others I hope find insight and resources towards what and how I set to accomplish the things I have in my scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/amarantos001.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3840&#34;
	height=&#34;2320&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal 5 screenshot. A mannequin in an A pose is facing four floating, large primitives. Between those is a fuzzy orb in a liquid metal appearance. It grows in an overpowering reds, oranges and yellows. It&amp;rsquo;s emission is picked up in real time through Lumen and casts light on the floating primitives next to it.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;165&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;397px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is the first screenshot I took inside the environment scene. An orange, abstract, floating, orb. This had been an experiment of importing an animated orb directly from Houdini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-beginning&#34;&gt;Project Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2022 I was experimenting with a small game prototype I had started in Unreal Engine 4. It was a topdown camera RPG with lots of spells and action. I never got to the part of prototyping much of this &amp;ldquo;action&amp;rdquo; but I did blueprint a lot of the initial movement, camera work, and then also had started on a few spells and abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t exactly be going into details about the prototype itself as that would call for another long post of its own, and would branch us away from the topic of this current scene. The context important to the start of this environment is that in early July 2022, after creating the initial Blueprints foundation for a few abilities inside the game, I set off to learn and experiment with Houdini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/amarantos002.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3840&#34;
	height=&#34;2320&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot from an UE4 game prototype. Gray, checkerboard landscape, seen from above, in a Diablo style camera. Few paths with a yellow tinted placeholer material connect to one another. In the middle of a screen is the player character. Up and right from her is a well prop with a mysterious red glow.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;165&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;397px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thought process behind getting into Houdini was that I wanted to create some spells VFX and animations. But the idea I had in mind was for fluidity and smooth movement, one that would be accomplished through fluid simulations. Yet for obvious performance and scaling reasons I could not get into creating actual real time fluid simulations (not that I have the knowledge to do that even if there is a way to scale it performance wise [I bet there is, smart people out there certainly have accomplished it]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/amarantos003.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3840&#34;
	height=&#34;2320&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Another screenshot from the prototype. The player character is in the middle and around them are floating orbs. Some are smooth and red in appearance. Like blood. Other copper and blue silver, looking like liquid metal.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;165&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;397px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These orbs above are my initial Houdini experiments, as seen imported inside my UE4 game prototype. They have a looping animation attached to them. You can see preview of it further down in this post in some of the YouTube embeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vertex-animation-textures&#34;&gt;Vertex Animation Textures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years prior I had heard a lot about the technique of baking down animations in vertex look-up tables. Those end up in the form of a bitmap that then is read from a shader in order to tell each triangle of the mesh how and where to move to. Interpolate between those different key &amp;ldquo;positions&amp;rdquo; on the texture and you get an animation (this is an incredibly oversimplified explanation, apologies to anyone that might be reading it and happen to be the type of Tech Artist to implement these amazing things from the absolute scratch!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of technique is called Vertex Animation Textures &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sidefx.com/tutorials/vertex-animation-textures-for-unreal/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;(VAT)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animations in the form of VAT have one incredible advantage over other type of game animations: it&amp;rsquo;s entirely driven in a shader. Onto the GPU. We don&amp;rsquo;t use or deploy any types of bones or skeletons and as such any object you animate in this way can end up as a Static Mesh. The animation, as I mentioned, then happens on the GPU through the reading of the vertex look-up table texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is memory footprint, of course. It comes in the form of the quite oversized in width and height look-up textures (which makes them have large file sizes). Also for a smooth and interesting &amp;ldquo;fluid&amp;rdquo; like animation, your Static Mesh might end up being quite rich on polycount too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vat-demonstration&#34;&gt;VAT Demonstration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this first picture you can see a fuzzy ball mesh I created parametrically in Houdini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/amarantos004.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1918&#34;
	height=&#34;1130&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Houdini screenshot. UI of the software is seen and in the left viewport one can inspect the fuzzy orb mesh.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;169&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;407px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then imported that mesh inside Unreal 4. I didn&amp;rsquo;t export it from Houdini as an ordinary static geometry. Instead I exported it as a VAT and in Unreal used a SideFX plugin and shader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/amarantos005.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1420&#34;
	height=&#34;980&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal 4 screenshot. Viewport look of the fuzzy orb mesh. It looks whole, top side reads &amp;ldquo;24,898 triangles&amp;rdquo;.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;144&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;347px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that orb, seen appearing like a proper mesh, is after the SideFX shader for reading VATs has been applied. If we ignore that shader and take a look at the geometry that the VAT exports, without material graph or the vertex look-up table textures that are generated, this is how it looks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/amarantos006.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1420&#34;
	height=&#34;977&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Another Unreal 4 screenshot. The same orb mesh seen above looked at again. Now the shader is not used and as such we see it as a giant, 3D matrix collection of triangles scattered in space.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;145&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;348px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned already, image above is orb imported in Unreal but no VAT textures are applied yet. As such its a collection of what to us appears like arbitrary placed triangles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;useful-vats&#34;&gt;Useful VATs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why use VATs in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we try to animate, say hundreds or thousands of actors onto the scene, all visible, even if they are incredibly low-poly, and use no complex textures to drag down our texture streaming budget, we often will still hit performance issues and hardly have any low MS (high FPS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for that is because when we display on the screen actors like that, ones with skeleton rig animations, they each end up being a separate draw call. Those draw calls go through the CPU and as such we end up being bound on CPU before we even get to use much of the potential that our GPU has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such the VAT is a trade-off where we might increase slightly the polycount, increase the use of textures budged, but end up with incredibly optimized amount of draw calls. The orbs you see above, I could render 100-200 of them in the scene, visible from one camera angle at all time, and still have low MS and good performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;animation&#34;&gt;Animation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above, there is also the more obvious part. It&amp;rsquo;s the content of the animations. In Houdini I wanted to make some fluids like sims that I could perhaps pull of through a shader in Unreal entirely. It would require of me to offset my orb surfaces with World Position Offset to give it a fuzzy, liquid like movement on its surface. But then if I wanted the visual to look proper and as cool as the ones in the VATs it would mean I need to recalculate my normals as well so light bounces off those WPO surface movements correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I will give a go at recalculating normals and making a shader like that at some point in Unreal. But for now I wanted to use the opportunity to learn fluid sims in Houdini and then learn VATs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5amuf5ohSr0&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Youtube embedded video above, showcasing an orb with fluid like movement animation.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The animation, seen after VAT import in Unreal. In this video below, the VAT shader is from SideFX but I have added control over Albedo, and Emission and I&amp;rsquo;ve plugged in a Fresnel function. It gives it the glowing effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SpGjcXyuz6A&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Youtube embedded video above, showcasing the VAT orbs but in UE5. These are now shaded and have more refined visuals.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly, I found all of the above incredibly interesting and fascinating, even before I dived to learn the nitty-gritty of it all. I am not really a VFX artist or an animator. But I do have a love for Tech Art (even if I&amp;rsquo;m not a Tech Art in my fulltime studio job either!). My setting off into making these type of fluid like animations for my spells came in big chunk through the motivation of me wanting to see if I have in me what it takes to learn and deploy these techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out I did. To no one surprise because as we usually do when it comes to most tooling and software in the games industry, we stand on the shoulders of those who came before us and concepted, created then implemented the techniques. A chorus of ingenious people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m saying this because after all of the descriptions above that might sound incredibly complicated to those of you who have not yet experimented or learnt this type of stuff, you might be left with the misconception that this is incredibly hard to create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s indeed not as complicated as it sounds. The biggest challenge I faced in learning Houdini was how to actually come up with my initial orb animation. When I did that, the moment I wanted to turn the anim timeline into a VAT and import it into Unreal, I had a bunch of tools already created for us by SideFX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to implement or write any shader. I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to automate any export - import. Those were all already available in Houdini (better yet, they come out of the box with exporters for UE4, UE5 and Unity alike).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this and hoping of trying these type of techniques, either follow the page I linked above (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sidefx.com/tutorials/vertex-animation-textures-for-unreal/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SideFX - VAT for Unreal&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or follow these videos, which I followed - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1cPRYwF-Tvg&amp;amp;list=PLoltx0CAXYf75OzQ3H_eGboHlrrf44gsi&amp;amp;index=1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;VAT 4 | RBD | Unreal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BaKNjIC66_8&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;VAT 5 | Fluids | Unreal&lt;/a&gt; - though I believe those two are just mirrors of the VAT link above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before getting into them I suggest watching some general videos of how to manipulate and animate geometry to look like its surface is changing, or even doing some fluid simulation tutorials. After all before you try to turn something into a VAT you want to make sure you have a Houdini animation ready in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create my orbs I experimented and at the end came up with a pipeline that creates geometrical primitives &amp;ndash; feeds them into Clouds &amp;ndash; feeds into VDB &amp;ndash; then VDB to Polygons. That with recalculated, smoothed normals produces results similar to the Houdini video I embedded under the &lt;strong&gt;6. Animation&lt;/strong&gt; section of this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to find out how to merge different orbs into an abstract structure, I recommend giving this video a go: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=47hkcRgCgzo&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=47hkcRgCgzo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s actually the one I started with. Later on, once I realized I want to try VATs, I winged it and added the &amp;ldquo;convert to clouds then convert to VDB then back to polygons&amp;rdquo; part I described above. I did that because I found that was the easiest way for me to add motion to the otherwise static orbs produced in the tutorial in the sentence above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;environment-scene&#34;&gt;Environment Scene&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I had made some floating orbs and they were animating nicely inside my UE4 game prototype, of course my Environment Artist side kicked in&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to think how even though I love using this inside the game prototype, it would be very fun to try and use it inside a polished, set dressed scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I briefly considered just creating a large, circular room inside my game itself. Then set dressing it and polishing it to a vertical slice. As if when you walk inside it you walk into a finished game environment. It wont matter if the entrance or the parts before that were placeholder and checker board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s around the time I got this story unfolding in my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the chamber shifted around them, their worship remained unmoving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular, repetitive room. Just a few modular pieces.
In the middle there is a shape that changes like fluid, using Houdini and VAT.
It has strong emission and perhaps could light the room entirely thanks to that and Lumen? Test it in UE5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shape will pulse and be animated thanks to the VAT and combination of Niagara curves and wave functions.
Next to it will be in circle a number of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are on their knees like in a ritual worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They move up and down their upper torso, while remaining in position, waving hands in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point the shape &amp;ldquo;glitches&amp;rdquo; into a bunch of triangles (try using a wrong Look Up Table / Textures for the VAT?).
As that happens, one of the people is lifted in the air, rotated 180 degrees and then slowly floated into the shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shape consumes them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;6 July 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got that story and jotted down those ideas above on paper, I knew I have to open a new scene and focus entire on that. I put my UE4 game prototype on the side shelf. I opened a new UE5 scene and started blocking out the space. The VAT Houdini orb I made would be the center piece. The jewel in the middle that I spent so much time on and learned so much through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-scene-shot&#34;&gt;Early Scene Shot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all of the above analyzed and described, we can now dive right into the environment side of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some hours of blocking out and making some initial building wall pieces in Blender, here is what I took the scene to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-001/amarantos007.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3162&#34;
	height=&#34;1779&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A circular room with placeholder gray materials and strong orange glow. There is a fuzzy, liquid metal orb in the very middle. Around are pillars with ornate details on their tops. The walls have slight gaps for sci-fi-esque windows. There is a door that is slightly ajar and sunlight comes out of it. Unreal 5 screenshot&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next blog post in this series we will take a look at my initial reference board. We will also see the different modular pieces I made in Blender and how I went about moving them into Zbrush and sculpting having in mind my end result will be used as Nanite meshes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed this post,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/amarantos-002/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
