<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Animal Shrine on Pete Dimitrov&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/categories/animal-shrine/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Animal Shrine on Pete Dimitrov&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://petedimitrovart.com/categories/animal-shrine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Interview - IndieWatch - Making &#34;The Animal Shrine&#34;</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/indiewatch-animal-shrine/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/indiewatch-animal-shrine/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/indiewatch-animal-shrine/indiewCover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Interview - IndieWatch - Making &#34;The Animal Shrine&#34;" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;forewords&#34;&gt;Forewords&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Towards the end of December 2018, few weeks after I wrapped up my project &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Animal Shrine&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I was approached online with an invitation to write about my process of creation. The invitation came from the creator of a website I had not heard of until then. The web was called &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IndieWatch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I loved the idea and quite honestly was immensely flattered that someone took the time to write to me, let alone invite me to be featured onto their website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Few years later this website closed and as such my article is sadly no longer up online. In order to bring it back to you here, I used a snapshot from 2022 as captured by Internet Achieve&amp;rsquo;s Wayback Machine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;article&#34;&gt;Article&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/indiewatch-animal-shrine/indiewatch-animal-shrine-2018.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1014&#34;
	height=&#34;567&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot from the article header on IndieWatch, 2018&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;429px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Dimitrov&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. I am a freelance illustrator and painter, who in the last 3 years stepped in the realms of 3D art. I started studying at the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;University of Central Lancashire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Preston, UK)&lt;/em&gt;, pursuing bachelors in &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. That is where I started to practice 3D for the first time (started around 2016. I will be graduating first quarter of 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was invited here, to write an article about the development of my latest, and as of now, first published 3D project. My debut in the medium, so to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One final disclaimer before we begin. In this article, I will briefly mention certain techniques but will link resources towards their use. I encourage you to look into them. Sadly I am limited in the number of things I can explain, as there is only so much I can cover without getting overly lengthy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name of the project is &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Animal Shrine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It is an entry for an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/contests/feudal-japan/challenges/51/submissions&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Artstation Challenge&lt;/a&gt; going by the topic of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feudal Japan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. But before we go into any explanations, I invite you to take a look at the full finished project, over at my portfolio, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/artwork/aRoa1k&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The project was created from scratch in 49 days. That was the length of the challenge. We were prohibited from using any libraries of 3D models or textures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;software&#34;&gt;Software:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, I will start by introducing you into my use of software. We all know that there are multiple programs out there, and a vast amount of ways to accomplish a certain task. My pipeline is an amalgamation of software that I’ve been taught to use at university plus lots of (and predominantly) self-taught techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole project is put together in &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unreal Engine 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve used one of the latest versions right now &lt;em&gt;(4.21)&lt;/em&gt;, deploying features ranging from being vital – for example for the look of my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xd7-rTzfmCo&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Volumetric Fog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; particle system; to small and relatively not important ones, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.unrealengine.com/en-us/Engine/Rendering/LightingAndShadows/SunPositioner&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Geographically Accurate Sun Positioning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (which I ended up not using at end, but is still a cool thing you can look into).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every prop and texture you see is created by me. For their making, I modeled most of them in &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autodesk Maya&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. At the start of the challenge, when I had more time, I turned every model into a high-poly one in &lt;em&gt;Maya&lt;/em&gt;, and then moved it into &lt;em&gt;Zbrush&lt;/em&gt; in order to increase the poly count even more and hand-sculpt some detail on the surfaces. I would then decimate the final result, and bake it into the low-poly version that I had UV-mapped prior to that. For mapping, I used the new &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zRaKwaQ9JAw&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Maya 2017 upgraded&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; UV editor. I got a few comments on how it must have been crazy mapping everything. It indeed was, but probably the sole reason I managed to make everything in the tight deadline of the 2 months we were given, was this new UV editor. A lot of stuff in it is automated and saves tons of time. One big example would be the feature to scale every UV island so that they match the texel density. Something, that prior to this would be done by eye, by applying a checker-board texture, and scaling up and down everything by hand, trying to match what you see. Well no more. By the end of the challenge, I sadly had no more time to hand-sculpt every detail. As such, I started to bake high-poly on low, without sculpting anything on the high. Might sound pointless, but you still generate Ambient Occlusion, Curvature and Thickness Maps, and they can be vital in the quick making of textures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When talking about baking maps, its good to mention where I do that. I used &lt;em&gt;Substance Painter&lt;/em&gt;. Baking any kinds of maps in that program, &lt;em&gt;Normals&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ambient Occlusion (AO)&lt;/em&gt;, or anything else, is literally like a child’s play. Use of &lt;em&gt;xNormal&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Maya&lt;/em&gt; for baking maps still exists in the industry, but I see no point in that, given that we have &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt;. Making your maps in it would be only a matter of firstly making sure that your UVs are created in a good way. Then, secondly, you turn your low into high-poly, export them separate making sure that they match locations. Most of the time you won’t even need a cage file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/indiewatch-animal-shrine/materials01_peter_dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot showcasing 8 Substance materials rendered on UV spheres. Paper, gold, porcelain, bamboo, ground mud, ground mud with moss, ground mud with puddles and final material is haystack.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a lot of materials in &lt;em&gt;Substance Designer&lt;/em&gt;. Those would be basic textures like wood, gold, paper, stone, ground dirt and so on. I noticed that I am very picky when it comes to wooden textures, and as such created around 2-3 very different in visual look materials. I wasn’t sure on which one to settle down, but it all turned out good as I realized that I can just combine them in different ways after importing them in &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt;, and achieve a lot of variety. I will share a few tips that require a bit more advanced knowledge in &lt;em&gt;Substance Designer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I exported every material as &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;( * ).sbsar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. I then imported that for use in &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt;. Its crazy how much you can do, if before exporting, you expose the right variables. In &lt;em&gt;Designer&lt;/em&gt;, the work you do goes into final nodes called &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outputs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. My suggestion would be to run your final results for each node into one final node before that. Expose said node and then have control over everything. For example: for &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Base Color&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, get your work into a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HSL Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, expose the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, expose the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and expose the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Put that into the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Output&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. For the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Normal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, expose the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intensity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Before the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roughness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; output, put a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; node, and expose every single aspect of it too. Now save that as &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;( * ).sbsar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Import it to &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt;. When you open it there and apply the material to part of your model, you will see that suddenly, if you don’t like the color, you can go in the parameters of the material (whilst still in &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt;, no need to go back to &lt;em&gt;Designer&lt;/em&gt;) and just tweak the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HSL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; sliders to your liking. You might import the finalized model into &lt;em&gt;Unreal&lt;/em&gt;. Suddenly you see that it’s too shiny for your liking. You can go into the material in &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt; again, and control the Levels you exposed in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roughness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and tweak everything to your liking once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/indiewatch-animal-shrine/materials02_peter_dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot showcasing 8 more Substance materials rendered on UV spheres. Wood warm, wood dark, wood red, wood rough. Second row showcases Smart Material set ups using custom masks and the first row of materials mentioned above. Between all materials you can also see a paper lamp and stone.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the stuff I said about exposing parameters might come out as a bit basic. But if you are smart about it, with just a little time investment you can create so much more. I created those basic wood materials you see and then exposed their color and roughness. Then, in &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt;, using &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Masks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (deploying the &lt;em&gt;Curvature&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Thickness&lt;/em&gt; masks I’ve baked), I combined different types of wood, changed their color and roughness, and basically created a few materials that inside &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt; I packed as &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Materials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Then whenever I had a new model, fully baked, I would just slap that &lt;em&gt;Smart Material&lt;/em&gt; on top and have a very good looking base to work off of in just a few clicks. For a project with such a tight deadline that was very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only software, that I’ve used and not yet mentioned, would be &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;World Machine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SpeedTree&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of self-explanatory by their names, I used &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A4f7uGCdhPI&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;World Machine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to create the mountains you see in the background. I am very much a beginner when it comes to that software, having picked it up for the first time only for this project. Still, its node based design, much like &lt;em&gt;Substance Designer&lt;/em&gt;, was not hard to navigate at all. I created a very basic looking mountain deploying different noises. From the software, I exported a high-poly base model. You can work on the texture there too, and export bitmaps, but I had no time to dive into that. Instead, I took my high-poly in &lt;em&gt;Zbrush&lt;/em&gt;. There I decimated it to low poly and used &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ObStsHYxags&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;UV Master&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to generate UVs. I took both into &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt;, baked channels, and used those channels to color it. It’s very easy, because stuff like the peaks of your mountain, go on a very specific value on the &lt;em&gt;Curvature&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Thickness&lt;/em&gt; bitmaps. As such, using some of the &lt;em&gt;Smart Masks&lt;/em&gt;, you can pick the very tips of the mountain, and color them in white, to have snow for example. Change the value of &lt;em&gt;Roughness&lt;/em&gt; to be shiny, and suddenly in under a minute, you have a very realistic looking mountain. I imported the model in &lt;em&gt;Unreal&lt;/em&gt;, and just spinning and scaling it around, faked some variety and very long mountain range by reusing the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/indiewatch-animal-shrine/53_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan_low.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1216&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;View of the mountain prop inside Painter. A few various props seen around too.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;157&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;378px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;foliage&#34;&gt;Foliage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the foliage you can see is created in &lt;em&gt;Maya&lt;/em&gt;. The bamboo tree you see close to the camera in some of the shots is assembled in &lt;em&gt;SpeedTree&lt;/em&gt;. The tree in the very distance is again created in &lt;em&gt;Maya&lt;/em&gt;. For their creation, I used a pipeline very well explained by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/artwork/EQQbA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karen Stanley&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I made basic low-poly leaves and grasses in &lt;em&gt;Maya&lt;/em&gt;. Some of them, I took into &lt;em&gt;Zbrush&lt;/em&gt; for some detailing. Those high-poly models, I then took into &lt;em&gt;Designer&lt;/em&gt; and having created a low-poly base plane and a cage, putting the foliage props in-between them, much like a pressing a flower between the pages of a book, I baked maps from which I colored and created my foliage textures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/indiewatch-animal-shrine/36_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1216&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Foliage creation.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;157&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;378px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This about covers the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;painting-and-2d-mediums&#34;&gt;Painting and 2D Mediums&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there is much I have no time to go through, as it would call for the writing of multiple tutorials and not just a single article! There is only one final note left that I want to make. When working on an environment like this, pay attention to how &lt;em&gt;the whole&lt;/em&gt; place looks. Look at the whole picture. Make smart decisions about your &lt;em&gt;layout&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;silhouette&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; that your buildings and props make. Look around with your camera and try to capture dynamic shots from the very beginning, even if most props are just gray-boxed placeholders. If your composition is boring from the very start, even the most detailed and pristine model, modeling and texture wise, will not fix your problem or make the picture look better. I feel like all of this is something that can be much more obvious in &lt;em&gt;painting&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;2D&lt;/em&gt;. Study composition making in &lt;em&gt;illustration&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;photography&lt;/em&gt;, even if you don’t have much of an interest in those mediums. They still can teach you a lot and improve the quality of your 3D work exponentially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/indiewatch-animal-shrine/19-shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1022&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Top-down orthographic view of the project, showing the development change I layout I did.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;187&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;450px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I can give you a good example of this project. I started the whole thing by containing it into one big rectangular shape. That would be a second, elevated level to which you go through some steps at the very front. I did lots of research and reference gathering before starting the project. My research told me, that in Japan, they indeed made shrines and places like the one I am creating, very contained, fenced in a very rectangular way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believably like that, did not change the fact, that even though I had some buildings even on another scaffold level, the whole place still looked very boring. I would fly around trying to pick some dynamic angles. I had few, but still not many, and even those came out a bit boring. At that point, as suggested by some friends and people over at my university, I decided to take a few of the buildings I had created to the ground level, and separate everything even more. That’s how the final layout was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;timelapse&#34;&gt;Timelapse&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I capture a lot of screenshots during the development. I assembled lots of them into one final, dev video. It overlooks the place in an aerial type of shot, before changing to a closer camera. You can clearly see what I explained there. You can watch it over on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bTylr2hF59c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bTylr2hF59c&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a pleasure to write this, and I do hope you find it useful and insightful. While working on our entries for the competition, we were requested to keep as detailed as a possible blog. To sort of prove that everything is indeed our work. You can go and read mine for some more tips and insight. Find it over &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-001/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I also created a sort of cinematic &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vi0vBi39h2g&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;fly-trough video&lt;/a&gt;, trying to convey a story I made up for the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vi0vBi39h2g&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to follow my work, you can do so over at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/peterdimitrov&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artstation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/peterdimitrovart/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instagram&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/PeterDimitrovArt&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take care, and if you liked the article, do keep an eye here on &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IndieWatch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; too. We might meet again for another one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;Enjoyed this article? Tip me on Ko-fi.&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 19 - Final</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/00shrineCover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 19 - Final" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-post&#34;&gt;Final Post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/00shrineCover.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Camera angle showing the mossy flat stones, leading to the middle of the picture where the main staircase is. It would take the viewer to the second vertical level of the shrine with the large, wooden structures. On the left of the image is the calligraphers hut. On the right is the overpowered in orange candlelight shrine.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we are. The end. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it. This is the first project of such a big scale that I&amp;rsquo;ve done in 3D, and it was quite the ride! As I promised, I worked a lot on a video, in order to show you the idea of the whole place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Animal Shrine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; As some of the Japanese texts I have on the walls of my calligraphers workshop suggest, this shrine is a place where you can leave gifts and pray to different animals. At first, it sounds like it is a thing for fortune, and good health, but read deeper and you shall come across sentences like &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those who bring gifts shall have powers&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Point at your enemies and the animals shall follow&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The commander of the animals&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before I say anything more, here is the video. Enjoy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-flythrough&#34;&gt;Video flythrough&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vi0vBi39h2g&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(YouTube video embedded above. It&amp;rsquo;s the main flythrough video showcase of the scene.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Japanese culture, as well as in lots of others, the animals I have depicted have a very common appearances. In Japan rabbits are thought to bring fertility, cranes were thought to be immortal and as such were considered secret. Frogs, some say, bring luck. All of that is referenced on the walls of the calligraphers, but I wanted to take it further. See if I could come up with something more mysterious and weird. And then actually have a go at executing it and telling it as a story through a video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was quite the challenge, I will tell you, and I redid that video about 4 times. Unreal&amp;rsquo;s Sequencer gave me lots of trouble too. It was good though, that along the way of making my props, I was exposing every single parameter possible. That gave me control over the colors of the lights, and the glowing eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/02-animal-shrine-peter-dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Main angle screenshot. To the left is the calligraphers hut with all the fortune scrolls attached to it. To the right is the circular shine with lots of animal statues in front of a water basin.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/03-animal-shrine-peter-dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Close up Unreal 4 screenshot of the entrance of the calligraphers hut. To the right one can see the green bamboo props.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/04-animal-shrine-peter-dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The interior of the calligraphers hut. In the middle is the tiny writing desk with pens and scroll on top. In the corners are lots of furniture. On the walls are many Japanese fortune scrolls.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/06-animal-shrine-peter-dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot overlooking the second vertical level of the scene, right after getting past the stone steps. To the left is a square stone cut with a lion statue sitting on top. Behind it are lots of tiny wooden supports on which sit the main structures of the place.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;process-timelapse-video&#34;&gt;Process timelapse video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a second video for you. A sort of a development time-lapse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bTylr2hF59c&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(YouTube video embedded above. Shows a timelapse of the building up of the entire scene, from the placeholders beginning to the end.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not take 431 screenshots, in order to have them unrecorded and not seen&amp;hellip; This is not all of them, of course, but I made sure to take lots of specific angles through the making, and them combine them in a video. Hope you find it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/07-animal-shrine-peter-dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Low angle screenshot, from the ground. Shows the circular shrine with the bamboo candles and the stone lantern. All of the lights are recolored from their ordinary orange, to a cold, magical blue. The animal statues now have their eyes light up and those are also in aggressive, white blue colors.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with this shot above, but I am leaving it down here, in the hopes that you first see it in the Video, and won&amp;rsquo;t get the whole surprise element spoiled.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now lets go to some technical talk. I recorded the scene in real time. The FPS is around 40-50 constant, but would occasionally drop down to 25-30 when looking through the cameras that overlook absolutely the whole place. I think you can feel a few frames drop on the first video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point I was kind of convinced that I will not be able to record anything in real time, given that I am pushing my models and textures to appeal visually at their best. LODs are something I would love to do, but maybe not in a short challenge like this. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to be very reasonable with my choice of texture sizes and my stacking of multiple objects on one texture sets. My machine is not bad, but it is by no means top-end either. I have a strong video card (gtx 1070), but pretty outdated CPU and only 8 gb of RAM. As such I am actually pretty happy with how the scene is running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;materials-and-callout-sheet&#34;&gt;Materials and Callout Sheet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see my materials and call-out sheet for my models:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/00-call-out-peter-dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Callout sheet image one. Shows the bamboo, foliage cards, the statues, all the animals, stone lanterns, stone steps, water basins, the mountain used in the backdrop but scaled down multiple times to fit the showcase callout sheet.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/01-call-out-peter-dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Callout sheet image two. Shows all of the wooden props. Those are the different pieces used to build up the houses and calligraphers hut. Next to them are the many paper and gold leaf fortune scrolls.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/materials01_peter_dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Material callout sheet one. Shows 8 UV spheres rendered from inside Substance Designer. In order of appearance: paper, gold leaf, ceramic, bamboo, ground mud, ground mud mossy, ground mud wet, hay.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First row: paper, gold, porcelain, bamboo. Second row is my landscape blending materials plus a weird looking hay I used for the &amp;ldquo;hanging rope&amp;rdquo; detail piece you can see in the second picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/materials02_peter_dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Material callout sheet two. Shows another 8 UV spheres. Between them are 2 tiny ones. In order of appearance: wood warm and light, wood darker, wood mahogany, wood mahogany intricate. The next 4 uv spheres are of &amp;ldquo;Smart Materials&amp;rdquo; set up in Substance Painter using the above previous 4. Those are wood and mossy stone surfaces. Between all spheres are the final 2 tiny ones that show paper lantern texture and base stone texture.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First row here is some basic wood materials I did in Substance. I then combined them in different ways, using Smart Masks in Painter. Last material is the stone I use in the scene. I made a simple one with exposed parameters for cracks and for hue. I then overlaid green version on top in order to make some cheap moss effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/05-animal-shrine-peter-dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Another screenshot from the UE4 scene. Shows an angled, close to the ground view of the calligraphers hut. To the left are some grasses and foliage obscuring the camera and blurred.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was lots of fun to do guys. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to bed all night. I mean, its morning here in the UK right now, but when I woke up around 20 hours ago, to begin work on this, I knew it was going to be my final day on it. It made me feel kind of weird, melancholic. It&amp;rsquo;s stupid, I know, but lots of you are so amazingly good at what you do, my only chance to catch up was to work crazy hours. And in those crazy hours, I got so used to this project, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m gonna feel empty for a quite a while, given that I will not wake up to have a stroll in it first thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank all of you out there for the kind comments and words I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten along the way here. Also, great thanks to all of my relatives, and friends, who put up with me, talking about this project, every. single. day&amp;hellip; Got quite a lot of support over at my university too, so thank you guys over there too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to mention my friend &lt;strong&gt;Rika Kanaya&lt;/strong&gt; again. She is the one behind the translations of my weird ideas from English to Japanese. She guided me through on how to put it in texts. Thank you Rika!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed my project, and I hope that the video and story gave you at least a bit of a kick-out. I think I will have a long break now. Maybe spend a week or two, just in the realms of the 2D, with some casual painting. :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. As always, have a good one. May we meet again in another project, just as fun as this one (but maybe, a titbit less stressful).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recollections-and-memories-update-from-2023&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recollections and memories. Update from 2023&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As I am here porting this old blog log into my new, personal blog website, I wanted to spend a few lines and talk about things I remember and recollect from this project. From the time I wrote the above at 4-5 am, in that sunless, British morning in my student accommodation flat over in Preston where I studied Game Design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above I talk about melancholy. I very much to this day remember the feeling and could go on to describe it in detail even now, 5 years later. Indeed, the daily opening and navigation of the scene branded into my mind strongly the space. For the following months, even a year and a bit after I finished this scene I remember having occasional moments of closing my eyes and in front of me, in my mind&amp;rsquo;s eye, seeing the Japanese scene.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was happening and was incredibly strong the few days after I finished the project so I occasionally had moments of pondering if this project will indeed be engrained into my DNA for the rest of my life and if I will be revisiting it in my nightly dreams all the time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve done quite a few more scenes and I don&amp;rsquo;t think any of them have come as close as to this one as being entangled into my mind and my psyche. That is even through the fact that most of my scenes after this one, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent more hours on and I&amp;rsquo;ve learned and done much better job at detail, space, texture, color and composition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There might be only one space so engrained into my mind, now that I think of it. That would perhaps be my section of the Sniper Elite 5 multiplayer map &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Flooded Village&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; that I worked on over at &lt;em&gt;Rebellion&lt;/em&gt;. If in the scene above I spent two and a bit months of opening it and navigating its space daily, then Flooded Village I have spend 3-4 times that. As such I got the same &amp;ldquo;Tetris effect&amp;rdquo; where on some days my mind wonders off and I go into a daydream. In that daydream I find myself into the space and zones of Flooded Village.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tech talk though&amp;ndash;things I got wrong above, in the initial post in 2018. I talk about pushing my visuals to the very max and as such my performance suffering when I am overlooking the entire Japanese scene. Well, yes, I did give it my max but back then my max was not that demanding on resources as detail in textures, and geometry, is relatively lacking. That is if you compare it to my current works. As such there was another missing piece of the puzzle. The piece dragging my performance down. That is &lt;strong&gt;draw calls&lt;/strong&gt;. Even though the lanterns you see above lack animations at the end, I did leave them as Movable Blueprints, as such splitting each lantern into its own, individual draw call. The little tiles that make up the paths, I scaled on the x;y;z in all kinds of fractions, splitting each and one of them into individual draw call as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve not run any profiling to see my draw calls in that scene (I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about it back in 2018). And I hardly have the time to go back into that project now and check, but I can guarantee you that indeed the draw calls are needlessly high.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As such whenever you work on your projects, pay attention to them. If you wish, you can read more about draw calls over&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-006/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(if you somehow missed the blog in the first place).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the gallery for &amp;ldquo;The Animal Shrine&amp;rdquo; with all of its screenshots and videos over &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/artwork/aRoa1k&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even with its problems this project still has a special place in my heart. Over time, in the last few years, I also realized that this is one of my most popular projects (most likely due to me writing about its process over at 80 lv website. Also being featured in The Rookies and getting printed in 3D Magazine thanks to a rubric about The Rookies.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since its making I think I&amp;rsquo;ve grown a lot and learned tons more about art, 3D, composition and crafting good spaces. Yet I try to embrace this project, knowing how much it&amp;rsquo;s enjoyed by most of the lovely people that follow my art online.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As such thank you very much for reading through the blogs about the making of this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you for all of the nice words, to those of you who have reached out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All the best,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pete.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 18 - World Machine</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-018/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-018/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-018/cover018.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 18 - World Machine" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-that-should-have-been-done-long-ago&#34;&gt;Things that should have been done long ago&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-018/cover018.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The camera angle looking at the staircase in the middle. Compared to the last blog post, this time around all of the colors are much more saturated. The Atmospheric Fog is very controlled and does not muddy up the scene. The sky is less busy even though appearing more detailed with proper colors. The lights all around the scene are much more controlled too.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My, my, I have a mountain in. It&amp;rsquo;s not like it was not a vital prop, and its not like there are just 2 days to go&amp;hellip; Priorities, right? It was super fun to do. I booted up &lt;em&gt;World Machine&lt;/em&gt; for the first time, and at the start wasn&amp;rsquo;t certain what I am getting into, but its node based design, just like &lt;em&gt;Substance&lt;/em&gt;, helped me navigate and get my bearing relatively easy. Exported high-poly from there, and took it to &lt;em&gt;Zbrush&lt;/em&gt; for decimation and then &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt; for baking and some color passes using the curvature and thickness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-018/53_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan_low.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1216&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;An image with 4 screenshots put together. First one is a Zbrush sculpt of a lion. Next is a Substance Painter screenshot showing a World Machine mountain prop being texture. Below is an Unreal 4 look of that same lion statue in the first picture, now being in use. Last image is that statue, but this time scaled down tiny, and used around the other small animal statues where the circular shrine and bamboo candles are.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;157&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;378px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell me that the screenshot from &lt;em&gt;Painter&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the mountain look like ice cream&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only consideration now, is that I&amp;rsquo;m not too sure how the trees in the distance fit in the scene. I tried to change them, I have better prop for them, but my FPS goes down crazily, even after quite a bit of optimisation. I prefer to keep those jaggedly trees, and be able to record a nice video with good FPS. I don&amp;rsquo;t want it for the fly-through of it, the scene is quite limited to viewing angles anyways, but I really want it for the telling of a story through it. One I&amp;rsquo;ve had in mind for ages now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shrine&#34;&gt;Shrine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-018/52_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan_low.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The main screenshot. The shrine with the circular steps seen to the right and all the little animal statues placed around. Just like the first picture in this entry, the colors here are much more controlled.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really needed that tiger statue in order to record the kind of video I want. I wanted to give it a more dynamic pose and so put it as if its ready to slap someone. Didn&amp;rsquo;t have much time to detail it, but it will do. Before moving it to that pose, I exported it sitting straight too though, in order to use that for the shrine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this is the last post, and next one is the final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, thanks for reading, have a good one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-019/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 17 - Paper Lanterns</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-017/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-017/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-017/cover017.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 17 - Paper Lanterns" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foliage-sky-and-props&#34;&gt;Foliage, Sky and Props&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-017/cover017.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Camera angle showing the mossy path leading to the stone stairs. Left is the calligraphers hut, right are the other structures. The sky now has a proper texture in pink shades with lots of white clouds littered on top.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started photo-bashing my own sky. Finally got into SpeedTree, and using the leaves that I created ages ago, plus a new bamboo texture, I produced a better looking result. My tree in the distance still needs replacing though. The mountains too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-017/48_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The main camera angle that shows the shrine with the orange bamboo candles to the right. All of the lights are much more controlled now. The previously square hanging lanterns (from the sides of each building) are now replaced for an oval, paper lanterns.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I toned down nearly every light in the scene. Especially the bamboo candles (which still need texturing, so sad&amp;hellip;). Also increased the area of lots of them, trying to achieve more clarity and go away from the small clusters of bright lights, that would be more appropriate for modern skyline, than a feudal village in the middle of the woods&amp;hellip; Could they do with more work? Sure, but we will see what can be done with the tight deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt like I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had a better opportunity to create spherical paper lanterns than this anytime soon. So that is what I did, an orange and a yellow version. I feel like they improved the mood and atmosphere quite a bit. They also made some of the random spotlights I had scattered around, feel like they actually have a source now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-017/50_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan_low.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;887&#34;
	height=&#34;562&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A gif with 4 screenshots. First 2 are the paper lanterns seen in UE4 and in Substance Painter. Next is a bamboo foliage build up inside SpeedTree. The last part is an animated shot, visualizing the new lanterns spinning in a crazy way, an annotation on top reads &amp;ldquo;You spin me right round, baby right round&amp;rdquo;.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;157&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;378px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The empty space in the Calligraphers, I filled a bit more, trying to tell a story of some sorts. It&amp;rsquo;s hard though, as I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to produce more props.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interior&#34;&gt;Interior&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-017/49_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1136&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot inside the calligraphers hut. Shows the writing desk. Behind it there are now 2 red sitting pillows. Next to them is a little tea set.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;169&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;405px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cushions are looking kind of shy, but we will see if I have any free time to work on them more. Before that, I feel like the floor material and walls need my attention first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any comments are much appreciated. As always, thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-018/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 16 - IKEA</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-016/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-016/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-016/cover016.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 16 - IKEA" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ikea&#34;&gt;IKEA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-016/cover016.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot from the very front of entering the calligraphers hut. Shows the interior with the hanging scrolls now fully textured in intricate gold leaf surfaces with red and black ink on top. The furniture around the place is now fully finished too. Only the scroll on the writing desk remains untextured yet.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally worked on those scrolls! I&amp;rsquo;ve been saying I will for what, maybe like 3-4 posts? Quite happy with how they turned out. I was worried that given that I fitted 25 of them in one texture set, there wont be enough texel density, and I wont be able to make them look proper. No matter if the texture were 1k or 2k. But they actually work quite well, even from up close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-016/44_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1216&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Few screenshots put into one. First and second are Substance Designer graph screenshots showing the paper and gold leaf textures. Then is a Substance Painter screenshot showing the above two surfaces being used in the final card textures of the fortune writing scrolls.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;157&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;378px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started them by making a paper and a sort of &amp;ldquo;gold leaf&amp;rdquo; materials in Designer. Got them in Painter, and then the first one I did, is actually the one with the branches detail. I went in Photoshop beforehand, and hand painted an alpha for it. I was quite happy to draw and paint once again, given that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the opportunity to do so since I&amp;rsquo;ve started this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-016/45_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1216&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Four more screenshots. Top is Maya view of the furniture used inside the hut. Right is an &amp;ldquo;Alpha used for golden calligraphy&amp;rdquo; that looks like a tree branch, hand painted in Photoshop. Below is an Unreal 4 screenshot showing one of the furniture with a vase prop sat on top. Next is the vase, seen in Substance Painter, showing its ceramic textures.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;157&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;378px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quickly realised, though, that I don&amp;rsquo;t really need alphas drawn in Photoshop, as I can draw just as good straight into Painter with the gold itself. I think this was the most fun thing I&amp;rsquo;ve done for the project so far. That vase is also hand-painted. So I hope you like it&amp;hellip; No pressure&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;hand-painted&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m kidding, its not that impressive once you turn the symmetry on. :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-016/46_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1029&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Another angle from Unreal 4 showing the calligraphers interior. Lots and lots of scrolls hanging from the walls, now seen in a close up with the gold leaf texture details and hand paints more obvious.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;186&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;447px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-screenshots&#34;&gt;More screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furniture texture is looking kind of rough here and there, but I will have to keep it like this if I want to actually accomplish everything I&amp;rsquo;ve planned. Also the textures on the walls call for a bit more attention as well, but we shall see about that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Any comments are appreciated. Have a good night from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-017/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 15 - Props</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-015/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-015/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-015/cover015.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 15 - Props" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;textures-and-new-props&#34;&gt;Textures and New Props&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-015/cover015.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Main camera angle screenshot from Unreal 4. The steps leading to the stone lantern on the shrine on the left are now proper static meshes with textures. The little lanterns are replaced for bamboo cuts with a flame inside them (like candles).&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progress 13 &lt;em&gt;(narrator from 2023: this was not his 13th post. He just could not count right back then)&lt;/em&gt;, what a fitting number. I just realised I have deleted one of my Zbrush sculpts&amp;hellip; I am nearly certain I won&amp;rsquo;t need it again, and even if I do, I can start off right from the decimated, exported version of it, but still, made me wonder where the heck I am looking when deleting files&amp;hellip; I blame Photoshop though, as it refused to launch and demanded for more &amp;ldquo;scratch disk space&amp;rdquo; and thus sent me into a chaotic &lt;em&gt;(and apparently unsuccessful)&lt;/em&gt; process of trying to tidy up my vast collection of rubbish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, I sculpted and textured the stones the big shrine goes onto and also worked on the shrine itself too. My first version of the stone texture had lots of bricks and extrusions on it. It was too detailed and noisy though, so I stepped back to the ordinary stone material. I still plan on scattering a few more small statues on top, and adding more candles too, so it surely wont be left without enough detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tweaked the lights in the calligraphers and actually created a proper light source prop for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-015/41_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Interior screenshot of the calligraphers hut. The walls are now textured and make the fortune writing scrolls hanging on the walls pop out. The floor has a texture too. There are square lamp props throwing yellow lights in all directions. In the middle is the writing desk.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;props&#34;&gt;Props&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Textured the tsukue (desk) and put an ink holder on top together with some ink blobs on the desk itself. I&amp;rsquo;m going to create a few pens and brushes that go on special stands, and one of them will be rolled and have spilled its ink, as if someone left in a hurry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-015/42_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1038&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Two screenshots put into one. To the left is the writing desk. One can observe a little ink set for writing sitting on top. Also an untextured scroll. The screenshot to the right shows the lantern prop.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;184&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;443px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve planned on quite a few more props to fill the empty space. Lets hope I manage to create them relatively quickly in the next day or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and as usually - those scrolls still need texturing&amp;hellip; I should get to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-016/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 14 - Calligraphers</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-014/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-014/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-014/cover014.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 14 - Calligraphers" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;textures-and-ornaments&#34;&gt;Textures and Ornaments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-014/cover014.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1148&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;High in the sky screenshot observing the calligraphers hut. The roof is now much more detailed, with golden ornaments on some surfaces. The Chigi and Katsuogi props on the roof now have proper oxidized metal textures.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;167&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;401px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I nearly finished texturing the whole exterior of the calligraphers workshop. Texturing this was a self-exploration in the sense of realising that I am incredibly picky when it comes to wood textures&amp;hellip; The result you see is a combination of 2-3 materials I made in Designer, combined with Smart Masks in Painter after a bake of high-poly sculpted quickly in Zbrush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll show you the materials properly rendered in Designer, but that will be later, as I am a bit too lazy to go back once again to those dreadful graphs (dreadful in the sense of I, going back to them multiple times, after realising that I&amp;rsquo;ve forgot to expose a specific value, exporting them multiple times, and relying to naming conventions similar but just as plainly unimaginative as &lt;em&gt;wooden01, wooden02, wood03_final, wood03_final01, wood_final_final&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-014/39_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1216&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;5 screenshots put into one. First one is lower angle UE4 view of the front of the calligraphers hut. It&amp;rsquo;s lit in a dramatic spotlight in white tint. Second is a Substance Painter screenshot of that same frontal piece used on the hut. Next is a Zbrush sculpt of a golden ornament. It&amp;rsquo;s followed by a Substance Designer screenshot of that 3D ornament baked onto flat, 2D texture and now properly colored in PBR gold. Last screenshot is the roof pieces in oxidized textures.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;157&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;378px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I tried to have some color variety in the wood itself, I knew that I will need to break it up with some ornaments. Also I really wanted to have something metallic in my scene. Every cool kid seems to have one texture set with just alphas for ornaments so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t skip on making one myself. I did that by baking in Designer some high-poly shapes I made in Maya and Zbrush. Using the Normal and Curvature together with deploying a vast number of Levels Nodes to get some specific edges, I build up some color and roughness variation in the gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I love about that pipeline is the fact that I can go back to my bake set-up, quickly add some more shapes, and after I do a new bake in Designer, the newly created shapes will instantly have the golden look without me having to do any more work. Also right now my texture set is 60-70% empty, so I have plenty of space to create some more interesting shapes and motives, instead of just the circles and the other one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I&amp;rsquo;ve illuminated the front of that building is very theatrical and dramatic. Although I really, really like it, I will most certainly tweak it later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is to model out some more furniture in there and also finally put some proper paper textures and roughness on those scrolls and posters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, thanks for reading. Have a good one from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-015/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 13 - Vegetation</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-013/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-013/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-013/cover013.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 13 - Vegetation" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vegetation&#34;&gt;Vegetation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-013/cover013.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Main camera screenshot. The parts of the ground that previously had flat, mossy texture, now also have 3D foliage props on top. In the very, very distant background, there are now trees. They are partially hidden by fog alpha cards.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the most of the time these last few days working on vegetation. I created a tree to scatter in the distance, some grass and a flower. The tree really makes me think that I should probably try SpeedTree, as what I produced cannot even begin to compare to what everyone else uses in their scenes thanks to the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, thanks god the tree is so far away, because let me tell you, for now it does not look impressive at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-013/36_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1216&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;3 screenshot put into one. First one is from Substance Designer and shows a bake of a branch and leaves card. Next is a Maya screenshot showing 4 different grasses and shrubs and flowers put onto a plane. Last screenshot is 3D cards building up the foliage. Text next to it reads &amp;ldquo;Some foliage. There is also a second bush of grass that is more dense. Ended up not using the last plant. Will change it to something else that works a bit better.&amp;rdquo;&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;157&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;378px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am somehow more happy with how the grass and flowers turned out though. I managed to model them and then bake and place some rough base color and roughness. I will have to go back and give them a bit more noise and detail later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-013/37_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1216&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Two Unreal 4 screenshot put together with some annotations. First one is a look at the support and stairs of the calligraphers hut. Text next to it reads &amp;ldquo;Updating with a wooden look some of the objects that lacked a texture.&amp;rdquo; Next screenshot shows bunch of stone lanterns. They are surrounded by statues, grass and flowers. Text reads &amp;ldquo;More statues! Also a closer look to what the foliage looks like right now.&amp;rdquo;.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;157&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;378px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve put more work on my landscape materials too, creating more detail. They could use with a bit more though, so I will keep working on that too in the days to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gif-progression&#34;&gt;Gif progression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a GIF:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-013/06-japan-peter-dimitrov02.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Progression gif that shows the adding of the new statues. Also the foliage that slowly gets populated on top of the landscape. In the background one can observe the jagged, placeholder tree cylinders getting replaced for proper static meshes.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I mentioned that I kind of struggled making the bricks path, and here you can see it in action. Also now you can agree/disagree with whether what I settled down with is the best from everything I tried with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 15 more days but if I don&amp;rsquo;t hurry up with all of the furniture and texturing for the calligraphers hut, I might not make it&amp;hellip; So next, I will try to focus on that. The foliage can have a revisit by the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-014/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 12 - Interior and Scrolls</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/cover012.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 12 - Interior and Scrolls" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-landscape-a-path-a-house&#34;&gt;A landscape, a path, a house&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/cover012.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Main camera screenshot. The orange glow from all light sources is much stronger and in a contrast with the ground that now has green moss motives. In the middle, towards the stone staircase, lots of mossy flat stones build up a path.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember how a few posts ago, I said I am quite happy to have a working Landscape Blending material? Well I was sort of wrong back then, as my tessellation wasn&amp;rsquo;t working. I knew that, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t as much matter back then as I had no height information. Well, the other day, when I created that height, it put me in quite the stressful situation of spending the whole day trying to figure out how to finish the blending of the height itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/29_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Another Unreal 4 screenshot showing the mossy path leading to the stone stairs. One can observe closer the landscape with its material blending too.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I got it working, then spend tiny bit of time on a grassy-mossy looking material and one that&amp;rsquo;s kind of rocky. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to post renders of them now, as they are far away from finished. Still, its nice to have some roughness information on the landscape. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have more grassy bits, but I will do that when I have proper foliage/flowers to put on top, because without that it will just look silly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brick path leading to the staircase that you can see, I redid about two or three times. First time it was too perfect. Then it was too chaotic and broken, with pieces everywhere. I tried elevating the whole thing. Then I tried having it go a bit inside the landscape. At the end I settled down on what you see now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, your eyes are not deceiving you—I finally have that calligraphers hut interior and some scrolls! (not finished and texture, but a progress nonetheless).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/30_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Look to the inside of the calligraphers hut. The platform it sits on is still a green, placeholder checkerboard. There are now lots of scrolls with Japanese writings and fortunes on them.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/31_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot of the interior of the calligraphers hut. It&amp;rsquo;s all in an overpowering yellow tint and tons of fortune scrolls with writings are hanging from the walls.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/32_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Same image as above, but at a slightly more frontal angle, looking as if you literally entered the calligraphers. In the middle is a little writing desk with a lamp and a scroll on top.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some thought into the text. As such I want to thank my good friend &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rika Kanaya&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for helping me with the translation to Japanese. Lots of the texts are just wishes for good fortune. Just like what my research led me believe is the common practice. But then we have a few sentences that lead to some story about the place. It&amp;rsquo;s meant to be a flavour text, so you wont be missing much if you, like me, can&amp;rsquo;t read Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few scrolls call the shrine an &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Animal Shrine&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Then some, like the very long one in the very middle of the picture above, explain that, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;hellip;this Shrine is a place for those who want to command the animals as their soldiers.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Among others are &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Spirits inhabit this place.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The statues shall come to life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Point at your enemies and the animals will follow.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. I made those so they lead to a story that I came up with the other week. The story is that you could leave gifts at the shrine and get involved in some kind of summoning ritual, where you can send thousands of critters after an enemy of yours. The animals would do your bidding. Its quite the fantasy spin, but that is what I like the most - fantasy works. I am hoping to be able to showcase that idea through my final video using some cheap effects, but honestly, I might not have the time to get that far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/33_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1216&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Four screenshots in total. First one is from Unreal 4 and shows 9 props that are stone surfaces, flat stones, water basins. Text next to those reads &amp;ldquo;9 objects, one texture set, yay efficiency.&amp;rdquo; Next is a Maya screenshot showing in line many fortune scrolls with Japanese writing. An arrow points to the texture used for that. A text next to that reads &amp;ldquo;26 scroll decals on one texture set. Oh my!&amp;rdquo;. To the right is another Maya screenshot. Shows an Unreal mannequin and next to it is a tiny tsukue writing desk. Text reads &amp;ldquo;A Tsukue (writing desk) for ants. Used real life measurements from a book, and they got something wrong if you ask me.&amp;rdquo;&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;157&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;378px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;construction&#34;&gt;Construction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/34_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot of the staircase section with the Foo Dogs. There is stone path under construction with stones scattered about but not yet placed in a good, final arrangement. In front is a yellow sign that reads &amp;ldquo;CAUTION WET FLOOR&amp;rdquo;.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(No, I didn&amp;rsquo;t waste my time modelling a sign, but still wanted to see one in there for the giggles. :P &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sketchfab.com/3d-models/wet-floor-sign-c65b36e817aa42faa0e46c953b5b3c76&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Courtesy of&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, thanks for reading! Have a good night from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-013/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 11 - Rabbit</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-011/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-011/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-011/cover011.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 11 - Rabbit" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;texturing-props-and-even-more-block-outs&#34;&gt;Texturing, props and even more block outs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-011/cover011.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal 4 screenshot of the what is now main camera angle. In the middle are few stone basins for water. Next to them are little animal statues: frogs and rabbits. Behind those are the steps with the stone lantern. Everything now has much more color and behind those elements are mossy stone surfaces.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally blocked out the calligraphers hut properly. It&amp;rsquo;s actually more than just a greybox, as I split the hut properly into finalised modular pieces, UV mapped most of them and even turned the front one that&amp;rsquo;s kind of dramatically lit in the picture, into a high-poly. It&amp;rsquo;s all ready for some arduous hand-sculpting in Zbrush before baking and texturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day I made a rabbit sculpture. Today I made two frogs. I have this idea that the shrine could be one for offerings towards animals like rabbits, frogs, turtles, cranes, foxes and so on. All of them are seen in specific ways in Japanese culture, and I could have references to that in the calligraphers hut with the scrolls on the walls. I mean, those are common animals, they have their role in every single culture, but still I thought it could be an interesting and nice way to fill in the empty space of the environment. Also its an opportunity for me to have a go at making my own sculpts and seeing what I can produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a grand idea about all of them tying up together in a specific way, to be seen in my final video fly-through, but we will see if I have the time to do it, so I won&amp;rsquo;t go into explaining it this early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-011/26_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;896&#34;
	height=&#34;712&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Close up of a stone bench with small, animal statues put on top. Frogs and rabbits.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;125&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;302px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, I finally sculpted and textured the staircase, the Komainu and the modular fence pieces. I am quite happy with the dog and the stairs, but those wood textures of the fencing could probably do with some more work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-011/27_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;921&#34;
	height=&#34;750&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The main staircase now has stone textures applied and proper, beveled and damaged edges (as opposed to the previous lowpoly placeholder). On each side, the Foo Dogs (Komainu) now have textures too.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;122&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;294px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are the modular pieces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-011/25_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1350&#34;
	height=&#34;804&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Checkerboard ground on top of which are laid out 3 static meshes. Those are modular pieces used for the wooden fencing.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;167&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;402px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll make some golden ornaments to break up the places in the wood where its too uniform (I mean, look at that corner piece&amp;hellip;), but I am more worried for the wood texture itself. I tried quite a few ones I made in Designer, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t like any of them. I will have to try again I presume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gif-progression&#34;&gt;Gif progression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted any GIFs in ages, lets have one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-011/06-japan-peter-dimitrov.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Progress gif showing the build up of the scene. Everything gets properly texture, the placeholder replaced for animal statues. The calligraphers hut takes slowly proper shape and its roof gets more and more intricate.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can notice the change in the calligraphers hut here easier. Something else too - I completely changed the source of the light in the scene. It was coming from the left, but I rotated it to go directly from the right (as seen from this camera angle). It put the right-hand side into a dramatic shadow, giving much more dynamic feel to the whole scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about the light-source also makes me think how I will need to work on the skybox at some point. It&amp;rsquo;s not seen much from this angle, but in my other main camera shot, we can see the sky quite a bit more. And then that reminds me that I need actual mountains and trees (or bamboo) in the distance. And all of that reminds me of even more unfinished stuff, but lets stop this rabbit-hole here. Ahhhh! Maybe I should have some rabbit holes too? Would be mysterious, right? Nah, I&amp;rsquo;m just kidding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a good night from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-012/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 10 - Wall Props</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-010/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-010/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-010/cover010.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 10 - Wall Props" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;props-and-pieces-and-a-meme&#34;&gt;Props and pieces (and a meme)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-010/cover010.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal 4 screenshot showing the shrine to the right. A little calligrapher&amp;rsquo;s hut to the left. On the right side, behind the shrine, there is lime-stone green, cobbled walls.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finalized modelling and texturing 2 modular pieces and a prop. I also did some work on the landscape actor. The textures on the land are a placeholder and the colors maybe a bit too red, but I am really happy with how my Landscape Blending Material works. Created it in a such a way that its very easy to include a new texture and also parameters for roughness and tiling amount are exposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the modular bits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-010/22_shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1076&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot showcasing a close up of the green, inclined, cobble walls.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;428px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go a bit heavier on geometry, because my main shots include those pieces repeated so much that they take quite a bit of screen space. Instead of tileable texture, I sculpted the two pieces, baked and then used my stone material I showed a few posts ago. Exposing HSV of it proved very useful as I was able to give it this green look that way. I might make the surface of the stones more light so they appear a bit more grey later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meme&#34;&gt;Meme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-010/modelmeme.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;584&#34;
	height=&#34;595&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A screen cap from the movie &amp;ldquo;10 Things I Hate About You&amp;rdquo;, turned into a meme that reads &amp;ldquo;I know you can model high poly and you can model low poly, but can you ever just model poly? - I think you can in Europe.&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually never seen the movie but came across the meme randomly.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;98&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;235px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A meme to illustrate my thoughts (image not mine, its a meme after all). In an ideal world for an ideal game, I would have to do lots of optimizing with a few LODs for that modular prop. But as its not gonna get repeated that much and as we are dealing with specific angle shots, I can save time and not do it. That&amp;rsquo;s the main reason I decided to go with geometry instead of Substance Designer made texture, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you like what you see, feel free to drop a comment. Good night from me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-011/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;commentary-from-2023-polycount&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Commentary from 2023 (polycount)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Back when I was making these stone, inclined beds above, I distinctively remember being incredibly worried that what I am creating is crazy amounts of high-poly. That whoever sees my work will see right past me and understand how inexperienced I am because of the high triangle count.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I could have not been further from the truth (even with that second part above, about being inexperienced, being true back then).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t quote you exact numbers but if memory serves me well, the stones wall prop was sitting around 1,800 - 2,000 tris.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That is absolutely acceptable. It is acceptable as a prop tris count now in 2023 and it was back in 2018 too. Not much has changed in the span of those years (well, if we ignore Nanite and the possibilities of UE5 right now, of course&amp;hellip;).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But the topic opens up a perfect opportunity to talk about triangle counts and preconceptions (and misconceptions) that fly around in students heads (like mine back then!).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will try to keep it short and to the point, so my advise now would be: do not take polycount advise from people who don&amp;rsquo;t know what draw calls or LODs are. Do not take polycount advise from people who will not ask the questions of what the intended game style is and what the main gameplay camera implementation is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Truth is you can get away with really high poly budgets for a single object. You can do that because you can then implement a few LODs that load much smaller polycount copies with the player going further away from the object.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a lot of student projects not only are there no LODs in sight, especially in projects that are FPS and would benefit immensely from it, but in most of them the draw calls are an absolute mess as well.
As such the performance of their game prototype is dragged down by mostly that: over the roof high amount of draw calls and crazy amount of overlapping dynamic lights.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Next when inevitably the question pops up, in their prototype, of &amp;ldquo;What is wrong with the performance?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;How do we regain back good performance?&amp;rdquo; lots and lots of inexperienced tutors will take a look at the screen and in a deep, pondering facial expression go: &amp;ldquo;Hmmmm, yes&amp;hellip; your props are way too highpoly and the amount of tris drawn on the screen are too high.&amp;rdquo;. Wrong.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analyze your draw calls first, look at your lights, consider some LODs and only then go cutting big percentages of polycount from objects that are most likely already lowpoly and optimized enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Unreal you can open the CMD (using the ¬ key on your keyboard) and type &amp;ldquo;stat scenerendering&amp;rdquo;. A menu will pop up that lists your amount of draw calls. Consider looking into ways to reduce them if they are high.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another very useful command is &amp;ldquo;ProfileGPU&amp;rdquo; that will open you up a much more detailed screen where you can see a breakdown of how much resources go where in ms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reading all of those is crucial for understanding better what the culprit of your performance is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want to read more about draw calls (though not a technical guide by any means) you can do so over at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-006/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;blog entry 6&lt;/a&gt; of this project where in my 2023 update I talk about it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-011/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 09 - Revamp on Layout</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-009/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-009/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-009/cover009.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 09 - Revamp on Layout" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;revamp-back-to-basics&#34;&gt;Revamp. Back to basics.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-009/cover009.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Unreal 4 screenshot showing the layout of the 3D scene. Everything is now moved around and reshuffled. The calligraphers hut is now on a level in Z lower than before. It sits to the right of the steps that lead to the main buildings. On the left of these steps is the shrine with the large, stone lantern.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing that painting and illustration has taught me better than any anything else, it&amp;rsquo;s the fact that sometimes you can feel in your gut that there is a problem in your composition, but you cloud your mind and decide to ignore it because of fear of failing in trying to fix it. The truth in nearly 10 out of 10 cases, though, is that if you put the time in and you do not ignore it, there is no chance you will not succeed in improving it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this environment, I could feel the square, too perfect shape. I thought that it fits nicely a shrine, or a temple like that. According to my research, in Japan they did build them in that fashion quite frequently. But that does not change the fact, that no matter what angle I would take with my camera, most of the shots were way too flat and kind of boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went in and used to my advantage the modularity of my props. I left the two main buildings elevated, but took the square hut and shrine down one level. I did that in hopes of capturing more dynamic shots with more interesting silhouettes and better shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-009/19-shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1022&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Top-down, orthographic view of the scene. The screenshot to the left is before. The screenshot to the right is after all the changes. On the right one can observe the layout being slightly less condense and on two levels of verticality. There is also more of a middle point - the stairs that lead to the second vertical level. &#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;187&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;450px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like it did improve quite a bit, and although I will still be posting shots capturing the whole place, I am going to stick to some specific angles and work on what is seen in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The textures you see for the landscape are placeholders (kind of obvious when you take a look at those roughness channel values).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-009/20_HighresScreenshot00168.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1310&#34;
	height=&#34;697&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot of the calligraphers hut. It&amp;rsquo;s lit in yellow from the interior. There are white, scroll blockout static meshes attached here and there, hanging.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;187&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;451px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my very first post I mentioned that I have a special idea for the square hut. I finally went in and blocked it. I want it to look like the workshop of a master calligrapher. All around on the walls and the entrance are hanging countless of scrolls with all sorts of fortunes written in beautiful calligraphy. It needs lots of work but I will try to keep it relatively simple and give it more detail with the scrolls. A good friend of mine from Japan will help me put some proper sentences and texts on those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-009/21_HighresScreenshot00168.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1310&#34;
	height=&#34;697&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Look specifically at the shrine where there are circular steps leading to a focal point of a stone lantern. On the little steps there are many tiny lanterns. They light up in oranges the otherwise gray area (UE4 screenshot).&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;187&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;451px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I placed some tiny lamps on the shrine, but the idea is that they will be candles put in bamboo sticks cut at a sharp angle. I blocked out a few shapes in front of it. One will be a trough and the ones next to it will be vases, plants and some statues at the very front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gif&#34;&gt;Gif&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We haven&amp;rsquo;t had a GIF for a while so here is one as usual. Starting from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-009/03-japan-peter-dimitrov02.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Gif progression that shows up the build up of the scene to have atmospheric fog, bet lit up and have textures on the landscape (dirt and green grass base texture). Then a big revamp in the entire layout happens.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you do agree that there is an improvement. I want to thank a few friends that gave me the valuable feedback of saying that the place was looking a bit too flat, even though I had it elevated and every single building was on a different construction level as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a few important props still missing, but I will get right to modelling those and then I will try to focus on getting finalized textures and models. I created a cobblestone material, which I still haven&amp;rsquo;t implemented in the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-009/japan_peter_dimitrov_mat03.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1318&#34;
	height=&#34;771&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;UV sphere screenshot from inside Substance Designer. Showcases circular stones. A pavement-like texture. Between the stones, in the gaps, there is green moss.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;170&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;410px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any comments are appreciated. Have a good night from me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-010/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 08 - Statues</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/cover008.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 08 - Statues" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;statues-textures-foliage&#34;&gt;Statues, textures, foliage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/cover008.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1244&#34;
	height=&#34;726&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshots of the steps just past the torii gate. In the middle, where the steps are, on both sides now sit Foo Dog sculptures. Guarding the entrance of this place. On the left and right outer sides of the image there are the many stone lanterns too.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;171&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;411px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t much created anything finished these last days. It has been more a process of exploration and learning of lots of things I had to go through. I started sculpting a Foo Dog, or what they call in Japan, a Komainu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/17-shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1004&#34;
	height=&#34;953&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Zbrush screenshot showing the Foo Dog sculpture. A dog with rabbit like backside has its right paw on an orb.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;105&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;252px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of it, in my opinion at least, is that statues like those which are actually old, fall in a weird, soft &amp;ldquo;uncanny valley&amp;rdquo; territory. Sculptors that made them obviously did the best they could for their time. Do you know whose else&amp;rsquo;s work falls in a category like that? Well, mine does. See, I don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience sculpting. But because I am making something &amp;ldquo;ancient&amp;rdquo;, I can get away with having weird proportions here and there. Although I did try to keep most of it appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor guy is still missing detail on his paws, but I&amp;rsquo;ll spend some time on that before I bake him. His backside also looks a bit like a squirrel, but its an improvement from the look of a incapacitated rabbit that he had at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might leave him looking a bit weird like that, because I can get away with it as of the aforementioned reasons. It might even add that extra charm and mystique to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was the lesser of my problems though. I started doing textures for the ground, and sadly I still don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to show although I did quite a bit of work. I did realize a lot of stuff though, and it keeps me positive that when I continue with it in the next days, I should have some successful materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a quick ordinary stone texture. Something to add to my library as I don&amp;rsquo;t want to use any of the Painter defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/japan_peter_dimitrov_mat02.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1318&#34;
	height=&#34;771&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Substance Designer UV sphere preview. A stone texture in gray colors and busy normal detail.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;170&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;410px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also exposed all of the values - hue, saturation and value + some parameters for how much and deep the cracks are. Should be quite useful and a lot of models that call for stone materials are waiting for me anyway. I will do a moss now and mix the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is another model. A detail, as I badly need those at this point, my scene is quite empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/08_haybell_peter_dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1010&#34;
	height=&#34;688&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Maya screenshot showing the wireframe of a twisted, bell-like structure made out of ropes that sits at some of the balconies as a decoration.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;146&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;352px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those big twisty bits and the things underneath them that look like bells right now, are made out of hay. Everything is tied together with ropes and looks quite immense and amazing to be fair. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass on having something like that. Gonna bake it on a lower poly model and do the hay in Substance Designer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me show you the reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/ref_haybell_peter_dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1010&#34;
	height=&#34;472&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Reference board screenshot showing two real life pictures from a place like Izumo Taisha Shrine. Showcases the twisted rope and hay bells.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;213&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;513px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as a final thought, today I started some foliage. I am doing a bamboo-like plant. I keep calling it bamboo, but it really isn&amp;rsquo;t. Its supposed to have thinner branch and lots of leaves that are more circular and spread out. Doing that in Maya, the leaves in Zbrush and then all baked and textured in Substance Designer (Thanks a lot to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/kazperstan&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Karen Stanley&lt;/a&gt; for her insightful tutorials. You are a life saver!):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/09_foliage_peter_dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1403&#34;
	height=&#34;871&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot from Maya to the left. Shows a foliage that is to be a bamboo. To the right is a Substance Designer screenshot showing a baked down leaf. To be used as foliage cards on the image to the left.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;161&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;386px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preview-screenshot-from-the-engine&#34;&gt;Preview screenshot from the engine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is how it looks in the engine, although it is by no means final:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/HighresScreenshot00134.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1121&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Preview in Unreal 4 of the foliage prop seen above. Next to it is a balcony and the static mesh of the hay bells that are work in progress.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;171&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;411px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think about it guys?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, for those of you who who made it through this long and boring blog post, and are reading this, I have a question. This foliage left me puzzled, as I haven&amp;rsquo;t really done any before&amp;hellip; Could you tell me how you do yours, guys? How do you put it in the engine and what options look the best? See, at the end, I left the mesh (imported and used as foliage with the foliage brush) to be dynamic. Leaving it to static, and baking lightmaps, at no matter what resolutions, produced a cluster of black rigged edges. No matter the size. Feels like increasing the resolution of the lightmap even makes it worse (does not make any sense).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scene is quite empty yet, I haven&amp;rsquo;t placed many pieces of foliage at all, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been really smart with my lightmaps resolutions so far. Not being able to bake this as static makes no sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks a lot. Any comments are much appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-009/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 07 - Bits and Pieces</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-007/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-007/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-007/cover007.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 07 - Bits and Pieces" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bits-and-pieces-and-a-plank&#34;&gt;Bits and pieces (and a plank)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-007/cover007.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;985&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Low ground camera shot from Unreal 4. Close to the front are lots of stone shrine lanterns. Steps take one upwards towards the main layout of the whole place. Part of a building is seen with its wooden balcony and supports lit in oranges through hanging lanterns. In the background where the landscape ends, one can now observe large, lowpoly mountains range.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;194&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;467px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally replaced those cylinders I had at the very front that were supposed to be shrines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were still some crucial bits that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have even in greybox. Mainly because I was pretty confident that I know how I want them and it wont take that much to do them. Was I right? Well it took me 3-4 different iterations of doing the same balcony before I settled down on what I like, so maybe I wasn&amp;rsquo;t right after all. But I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what - it felt refreshing and nice to do it after falling in the hole of &amp;ldquo;oh is this texture worth anything&amp;rdquo; yesterday and the day before that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-007/15-shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1259&#34;
	height=&#34;646&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot of one of the buildings that sits on the most densely populated wooden supports. Lots of placeholder trees in the background (simple cylinders) and a lowpoly mountains range.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;194&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;467px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Props are still placeholders and some lack textures. Then there is the very long roof which is 3 shrunk huge roofs and thus the baked AO that has left marks as if from burnt. The bits that are not textured though I even UV mapped so it should be relatively quick to give them the wooden look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still working on the texture of the roof that you see on the big one. First version was very grey and dark, then I went into more of a brown warm wood look which helped a lot. The bits on the very top are gonna be metal and have oxidized green parts (bronze) that I hope will contrast nicely with the wood. Still I feel like it lacks a bit of variation and texture and as such I will go over the edges and add metal ornaments/rain plates and so on, that will hopefully break up the wood and make it more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an ordinary wood planks texture I did in Substance Designer to go on the walls:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-007/japan_peter_dimitrov_mat01.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1318&#34;
	height=&#34;771&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;UV sphere screenshot from Substance Designer. Shows a wooden plank material, in a slightly stylized detail.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;170&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;410px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I though it was very boring and dull and is gonna look bad in Unreal. Turns out that wooden walls are very much ordinary, and maybe its for the best not to have anything crazy going on. I think i will leave it like that for now, see how it works with the metal and with the rest of the textures in the scene, and then maybe come back to it and add detail, make it actually realistic or completely change it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gif-time&#34;&gt;Gif time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-007/05-japan-peter-dimitrov.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Progress gif from the angle where one can observer the dense, wooden supports. There is now a build up of balcony and shaded roof parts too. Place goes from unlit and flat to having hanging lanterns with dramatic, orange spotlights that have strong influence on the Volumetric Fog used in UE4.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GIFs remind me of one last thought that I have about my scene development. Most of the angles I show in the GIFs have the thinking of &amp;ldquo;what would be the best angle to fit everything in the picture and show my progression in the most transparent way&amp;rdquo;. Thus the far-away aerial shots from some of the previous posts. What I really should do soon though, is pick some specific angles that look good and make the scene justice. Then I will have to stick to those and make sure they above all look the best so I can use them as final images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea behind my whole level and development here is that I want the scene to have a &amp;ldquo;game ready&amp;rdquo; look, where if you throw the player in, no matter First or 3rd Person, they can traverse anywhere and everything will look perfect from any angle. Will that work though? I might have to accept the fact that I might not be able to do that for the short deadline we have. Not with the quality that I want anyway. And if that is the case, then I need to have proper angles and bits where I can fall back to and know that they will work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now though, I&amp;rsquo;m sticking to the &amp;ldquo;game ready&amp;rdquo; mentality, no matter the size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, comments are much appreciated and have a good night from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-008/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 06 - Lamps</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-006/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-006/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-006/cover006.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 06 - Lamps" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lights-in&#34;&gt;Lights In&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I modelled some hanging lanterns. I really needed to put some object that cast actual interesting light in my scene so I can start thinking about my light scenario. It&amp;rsquo;s still in the early stages and looks patchy in the sense of having a lot at of light at one place and then none at others, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on it more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-006/cover006.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot of a camera between two buildings, close to them, Unreal 4. One can observer the wooden beams and supports, fully textured now. The roof has a wooden texture as well. There are hanging lantern props that cast some Point Lights too. In the distance, where the landscape ends, there are long, sharp cylinders that are indicating placeholder trees creating a forest.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I sculpted a bit more the landscape around the place. I also scattered a lot of placeholders for the trees. It changed the mood of the whole place immediately in a way that I really like. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to look into how I&amp;rsquo;m going to make the trees and what to do with my mountains in the distance (they are just placeholder big boulders for now). I&amp;rsquo;m open to any suggestions and tips when it comes to creating the landscape guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But back to the lanterns, they were kind of very fun to do. Their process was interesting to say the least. Right now they are an Actor (Blueprint) attached with a rope and a Physics Constraint. That way I can apply physics to them and use Impulse to add force and nudge them in one direction. Gives them a slight animation and it makes such a big difference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While making them, I had to explore how the Physics Blueprints work in Unreal as I had never used them before. It produced an interesting result. Just when I thought that none of the Blueprints worked even the slightest, I looked up and saw a few lanterns suspended in the air, rotating around as if in zero G.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wOTc2GFSAnU&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(YouTube video embedded above. Shows a hanging lantern that is suspended in open air and floats around as if the place has zero gravity.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have them working now, and its something that I believe will add quite a bit to my scene when it comes to the final rendering videos. Also now I know how to do stuff like that for any other object I might want to implement that could be moving. Only thing left now is to actually texture those lanterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-in-my-every-post-its-time-for-a-gif-now&#34;&gt;As in my every post, its time for a GIF now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-006/04-japan-peter-dimitrov.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Gif progression preview. Shows the build up of the wooden structures up to the point of the support beams having a texture. Then the adding of fog, lanterns and placeholder trees in the background.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to change the fog once again in order to make the &amp;ldquo;trees&amp;rdquo; in the distance appear lighter and thus look even further away. The fog changed how my roofs look though, made them maybe too light for my liking. The Volumetric Fog and Atmosphere actors are things I will have to tweak a lot more before I get to what I imagine, but at least there is progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That will be from me tonight guys, have a good one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-007/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;commentary-from-2023-draw-calls-tips&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Commentary from 2023 (draw calls tips)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wanted to quickly drop a few words about some of the things I showcase above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knowing what I know now, in 2023, compared to back in 2018, I would not approach making these lanterns with Physics Components at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is fun to experiment with Physics Components in Blueprints. If you have not had the chance to do so before, make sure to try as I think there is plenty to learn. There is something I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about back then though, and it&amp;rsquo;s a fundamental part of Tech Art and of creating optimized, real time scenes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That is draw calls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For Physics to work, we need to make the lanterns mesh &amp;ldquo;Movable&amp;rdquo; as opposed to &amp;ldquo;Static&amp;rdquo;. The moment we do that, we separate that piece of geometry in its own draw call.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lets run a hypothetical situation:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We leave the lantern static - like ordinary geometry.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We scatter 10 copies of it near one another.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then we make sure the material used on all 10 copies is identical.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On the scaling options of each we leave it to 1;1;1 on the x;y;z scale.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A great thing happens; the moment those 10 lanterns get to render on the screen they batch into a single draw call. This keeps it all more optimized.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If we are in a blank scene and we render 10 lanterns in 1 draw call as opposed to 10 lanterns in 10 draw calls, we might not feel much of a difference, even if we inspect the fps / ms and profile the entire scene both GPU and CPU wise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imagine increasing up the numbers and putting 100-200 even 1000 of these lanterns on the screen. Suddenly rendering all in 1 draw call as opposed to 1000 draw calls can be felt. Then add up all kinds of other art assets on the screen, some static, some movable. Add a bunch of fog cards and alpha card effects that are overdrawing the screen. Add lots of AI running on the CPU. Add some particles, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you pick to scale them onto the CPU or the GPU. Suddenly you get the typical amount of things happening in a usual game world in a big AAA title.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Your performance will then be low, if you were to render these lanterns in 1000 draw calls instead of 1 draw call.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The lesson here being that we always need to consider clean practices of putting in art meshes so they end up as optimized and bundle in draw calls as possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I can hear you wondering, though, how are we to then make these lanterns move and look interesting? Without dirtying up our draw calls?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some might suggest doing a bespoke bone animation and then attaching it to the lantern. We animate it in Blender or Maya and import in Unreal. But that will have the same culprit of an issue as above. Animated assets with bones of their own most of the time end up as separate draw calls (there are ways to overcome that and still keep bone animations but that is for another blog).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As such a better way instead would be to ask the following. Is there a way I can bundle all of this movement onto the GPU? When you ask that question the follow up conclusion would be: yes! You can. Through a material shader perhaps? That&amp;rsquo;s on the GPU, right?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Absolutely. If we create this entire animation of moving the lantern in some direction, as if slightly moved by wind, inside the shader, then it means the geometry when placed in the world can remain Static. When it remains static it means our draw calls are back to being easier to manage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My suggestion for getting that done would be to 0.0.0 your pivot point of the mesh to where the upper cable of the lantern is. Export like that and put into Unreal. In a special material shader for the lantern then, create a World Position Offset (WPO) that slightly rotates everything in whichever axis you like. If you add a little Sine animation multiplier to that, inside the WPO numbers, you will get exactly a bit of movement as if pushed by the wind. Apply that to all other lanterns now and they will all bundle into draw calls, as long as using the same material and their scale in the world is similar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you dislike the lantern movement being similar between all of them, you could introduce a bit of a random number multiplier in the shader to overcome it. Or you could expose a number that controls it, and in a material instance of the original parent put in your own animation offset as a number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you do that second option though, consider making just 3-4 material instances and then applying them to your 300-400 lanterns in the scene so they all end up in 3-4 draw calls. If you go out of your way to make a unique instance for each lantern then we are back to square one and we end up with all of them having a unique draw call (kind of bad).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know I quickly gloss over the last few tips, but I intend to give you the names of the techniques and resources you could look up online and I believe you can accomplish whatever it is you imagine using that. The tricky part is knowing, and being aware of it all in the first place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That is the part I struggled with the most before I joined the industry professionally. At my university for 3 years course not once were the words &amp;ldquo;draw calls&amp;rdquo; mentioned. When people talked about optimization everyone jumped to &amp;ldquo;oh well, its just too highpoly&amp;rdquo;. Though even back then I knew that clearly is not the case, it still took me years before I first realized about draw calls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quite honestly, being in the industry now, I will tell you that even some professionals go for years unaware about draw calls. They talk and talk about lowpoly and highpoly but never consider their draw calls or implementing LODs to increase performance. But this would be a conversation for another time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As for now, if you are a student or someone getting into things just now, and in this blog you for the first time came across the concept of draw calls, then I take it this was helpful and the idea of it leaves me happy. Now go on and look up some more engine docs and videos on draw calls and supplement and increase your knowledge even more!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pete.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-007/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 05 - Hansel and Gretel</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-005/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-005/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-005/cover005.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 05 - Hansel and Gretel" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-fom-yesterday-and-today&#34;&gt;Work fom yesterday and today&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I started texturing. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t planing on starting this soon, but I wanted to have a preview of what is to be. I also knew that I will go for a pipeline that I haven&amp;rsquo;t mastered before, so I wanted to make sure I can do it properly. I started with objects I have the exact dimensions of. That is the wooden supports that go around the place to create the &amp;ldquo;scaffolding&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the result:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-005/cover005.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1263&#34;
	height=&#34;669&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Close up screenshot of one of the buildings the the wooden structure it sits on. The wooden supports are now texture in a worn, aged wood.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;188&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;453px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that I wanted a wooden texture, but to be fair I imagined I will need to do a detailed pass of Substance Designer and then use that in Painter to layer out more finished non-tillable texture feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I got the object in Zbrush, did a high-poly detailed sculpt of it and then baked it on low poly. I then layered a few colors together using the Curvature mask that Substance Painter bakes. The result is what you see, and to be honest I am pretty happy with it. If I manage to give everything else the same level of detail, I reckon it should be good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the image above, I modelled the basic shapes of the house a bit more. It got me, to what looks like in Maya, a Hansel and Gretel House. Note, I&amp;rsquo;ve marked with reddish color, shapes that don&amp;rsquo;t matter. What is white, is the shapes I need to bake and texture and then repeat to get the rest (the roof of course will be a piece of its own, with and UV of its own).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-005/03_building_peter_dimitrov.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1375&#34;
	height=&#34;856&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Maya screenshot showing the main building and the different pieces its made of. The gray colored parts of the building are the ones that will have unique texturing. The others (the reddish color) will either be mirrored or use tileable textures.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;160&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;385px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with modular pieces quite a bit (as seen in the wooden supports). I realized that I can do much more with less models than I imagined at first. After I learned my lesson with the wooden supports, I made sure to make the most out of the shapes I create with the house models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-always-lets-do-a-gif-my-favorite&#34;&gt;As always, lets do a GIF! My favorite.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-005/01-japan-peter-dimitrov02.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Gif progression from the frontal part of the shrine where the torii gate is. One can inspect the slow build up of the scene up until parts of the buildings start to have textures and proper fences static meshes go into place.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note, I haven&amp;rsquo;t put much work into the lighting scenario. I am really happy with the modular pieces though, because they are really low poly and I managed to get the most out of them by baking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see them laid out here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-005/HighresScreenshot00075.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1263&#34;
	height=&#34;796&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Checkerboard landscape with 7 support, wooden beam static mesh props on top. Unreal 4 screenshot.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;158&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;380px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I did is two big pieces (a part from the very small one) I modelled those those out - sculpted them in high detail - and then baked. Then I cut the pieces in the very middle. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to do any changes on the UV or textures. I managed to get 2 extra pieces out of one sculpt. And that did make quite the big difference. Using those, I could manage to recreated and replace all of the basic brushes in Unreal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something else - quite obvious but still - a cube (or parallelepiped) has 4 sides. If you sculpt and bake those properly, you can rotate the same object each time you repeat it and get enough variation out of it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m gonna texture the new pieces I did for the main buildings soon (the emissive windows and etc.) and I hope it looks good. I&amp;rsquo;ll share all of the results with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good night from me, and I hope you are doing great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-006/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 04 - Fences</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-004/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-004/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-004/cover004.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 04 - Fences" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-from-today-and-yesterday&#34;&gt;Work from today and yesterday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general I&amp;rsquo;ve been going around and replacing Unreal basic brushes with proper models. Takes a bit more time, as I try to model them in a way that they are ready to jump in for high-poly and Zbrush before baking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve been mastering my technique of making smooth roofs by now. I did one 3 times, wasn&amp;rsquo;t happy at all with the result and then came up with better idea of how to do it just when I was drowsing off having a rest in my bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I am most happy about, though, is my modular pieces for the fencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-004/cover004.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Slight aerial camera view from the front of the Shrine and the steps leading upwards to the buildings. At the start is a torii gate. There are now little posts with lamps that throw some oranges. The place has an eerie atmospheric fog too.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 3 pieces in total. One that repeats to create the main fencing, one corner and on edge bit that I use at the very front gate. I&amp;rsquo;m really happy how they fit together and that there are no weird lines and shadows where the pieces meet (only weird lines right now are from the quick placeholder UVs that distort the texture).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also increased the fog a bit, which will interfere with my perfect aerial shot GIFs, making it harder to see, but oh well. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-004/09-shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Lower, dramatic angle UE4 screenshot showing the blockout of lots and lots of wooden beams that build up a traditional Feudal Japan style platforms that then support a building.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a square gazebo of sorts (not sure what the proper name is) that I&amp;rsquo;ve placed at the very entrance of each big building. I also made some lamps that at first looked like Old London light posts&amp;hellip; They are a bit better now but still really need a texture to convey at best what they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a Shrine now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-004/10-shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1240&#34;
	height=&#34;675&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A shrine screenshot. Steps in a circular manner all condense towards a focal point where there is a stone lantern post.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;183&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;440px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gif-progress-view&#34;&gt;Gif progress view&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, its time for my favourite part, a GIF! Lets have one that starts from the very beginning and gets to the current state:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-004/02-japan-peter-dimitrov03.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Side camera gif progression animation. Shows the build up on the roofs from the last post but then the build up of the calligraphers hut, the atmospheric fog and other Unreal 4 effects.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, thanks for reading and have a good night!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-005/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 03 - Roof</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-003/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-003/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-003/cover003.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 03 - Roof" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;roofing&#34;&gt;Roofing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of the hours I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on the project today on the roofs of the buildings. I started doing that in Maya, modelling them in such a way that they are good enough to be turned into high-poly, then baked and textured. I&amp;rsquo;ll add more detail on them before I do that of course, but its nice to finally see them in and realise what silhouettes the buildings create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-003/cover003.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A view (screenshot from Unreal) showing close up, in a dark spot between two buildings. This time around, the structures have roofing that looks in a typical, Feudal Japan style (sharp angle, large decorative pieces on the top).&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is a GIF:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-003/02-japan-peter-dimitrov02.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Progression gif that shows the build up of the steep angled roofs and their details on the top.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are really smooth and lack any tiling mainly because I imagine them to be from wood. The reference I am looking at in this case, is the Izumo Taisha Shrine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-003/07-shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1756&#34;
	height=&#34;1357&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A reference board screenshot. Includes three pictures from Izumo Taisha Shrine.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;129&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;310px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll replicate the texture in Substance Designer later on use it on the roofing. My only consideration is that they might be left looking a bit bare and not finished at the end. I think it has to do with the fact that, when we talk about Japanese or Chinese buildings of this style, we always imagine one covered in numerous pretty, circular tiles. As such by the end I might collide a few different styles and end up with something of my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;here-is-a-close-up-of-the-work&#34;&gt;Here is a close up of the work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-003/04-shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1330&#34;
	height=&#34;777&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Very close up UE4 screenshot of the roof and the intricate details (that are lowpoly blockout still). Those are roof parts like Katsuogi, Chigi, Iraka-oi.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;171&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;410px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-003/05-shot-peter-dimitrov-japan.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1330&#34;
	height=&#34;777&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A frontal screenshot from UE4 showing the calligraphers hut blockout. Unlike the other, more prolonged buildings, this one is nearing a perfect square. Next to it is an Unreal 4 mannequin showing its scale in comparison to a typical human.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;171&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;410px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any comments are much appreciated. Good night from me guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-004/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 02 - Blockout</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-002/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-002/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-002/cover002.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 02 - Blockout" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;greyboxing&#34;&gt;Greyboxing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been greyboxing the concept for my level for a few hours now. I&amp;rsquo;m quite excited how its shaping already and wanted to update all of you with some screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I did a sketch on paper looking at the level top-down. In that one, I made every single shape and the buildings square. Today, playing with the shapes in Unreal, I decided that I want to break up the level a bit more than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-002/cover002.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;First look at the 3D scene blockout. Unreal 4 screenshot. High level camera view of a blocked out space with little huts that still don&amp;rsquo;t have roofs. Everything uses checkerboard, placeholder, blockout materials. Some gray, other green checkerboards.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be sure that there is variety in height too, and as such I elevated the whole place. I created wooden structures for each building to sit on. I still don&amp;rsquo;t have the roofs, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think its much worth it to even greybox them in Unreal. Making them to look like anything, even for illustrative purposes, will take far too long, and now that I have figured most of the measurements I can just dive into Maya and make them there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fencing around the whole place will be from stone. It will also have its own mini triangular roofing that is probably gonna be wooden (in the style of the rest of the buildings). For the square building to the right I have an interesting idea, but I will share it with you given that everything else goes according to plan the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some progress GIFs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-002/01-japan-peter-dimitrov.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Gif preview showing the progression of building up the blockout. It all starts first with simple rectangular platforms only to later be build up by smaller &amp;ldquo;wooden&amp;rdquo; structures of supports that then host other square buildings on top.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of fun to see it get built like this in an animation, as if some invisible workers are putting it in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An angular shot for a better view:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-002/02-japan-peter-dimitrov.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Identical gif progressions preview as above (as in the action is the same). The difference is that the camera is a bit more to the side.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is an aerial shot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-002/03-japan-peter-dimitrov.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;563&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The gif progression seen in the two files above, but this time around from a camera nearing a top down look. The progress on building up the layout can be showcased much more easily here.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-work&#34;&gt;Further work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m imagining prolific and bulky (but smooth) triangular roofs that go on 2 or even 3 levels. I think they will compliment the squarish shapes underneath and create some interesting silhouettes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the whole place I want to scatter lots of trees, as to make this whole place in a remote, tranquil location. In one of the reference books that I got, the author put it so nicely in words, that its quite the inspiration for me &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;the plains would have formed a veritable sea of trees, their tips stretching into the distance like waves.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, given technical limitations on the number of trees I can have and also the fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve never done a serious foliage before, let alone a tree, we shall see if I manage to accomplish view worthy of that description. But that is something for the very end, and as such not worth any worry right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that you like what you see and that your projects are coming along nicely guys! Until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-003/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Animal Shrine - 01 - Start</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-001/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-001/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-001/japanCover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Animal Shrine - 01 - Start" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-and-references&#34;&gt;Research and References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-001/japanCover.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1380&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A moodboard screenshot that includes 17 images, drawings, old photographs and more of Feudal Japanese architecture, huts, gates.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;139&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;333px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to create a scene where the whole concept is mine. As such I decided not to use any art from the Environment Design category. I gathered some images and put them in one sheet in order to have the basic mood and ideas there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that I&amp;rsquo;m not using any concept pieces, I was worried that I might struggle a bit. As such yesterday I visited my University&amp;rsquo;s library in order to do some research and get some books on the topic. I borrowed 3 books on the topic as you can see below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-001/peter-dimitrov-books_compress.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1920&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A photo of two books. One is open, the other on top is closed. The one on top is &amp;#34; Japans Wooden Heritage&amp;#34; by Terunobu Fujimori and Mitsumasa Fujitsuka. Translated by Hart Larrabee.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading about the different buildings will help me immensely, as I feel like I need to know their purpose, not only their visual appearance. As you can see in the picture I&amp;rsquo;ve already went crazy with bookmarking quite a lot of pages. At some point it got so much, that I had to start even putting notes on the bookmarks to keep up with whats going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some sketches on paper and initial idea of the layout of my environment, but more to come possibly tonight. I&amp;rsquo;ll update you with some Unreal progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://petedimitrovart.com/p/animal-shrine-002/&#34;  title=&#34;index.md&#34;
    &gt;Go to next blog entry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;https://storage.ko-fi.com/cdn/widget/Widget_2.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;kofiwidget2.init(&#39;If you find my blogs useful, tip me on Ko-fi&#39;, &#39;#428beb&#39;, &#39;W7W4LKBRP&#39;);kofiwidget2.draw();&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
