<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Pages on Pete Dimitrov&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/page/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Pages on Pete Dimitrov&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://petedimitrovart.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a British-Bulgarian, Senior Environment Artist, currently working at Rebellion, Liverpool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released game titles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sniper Elite: Resistance &lt;em&gt;(PC, Xbox, PS5)&lt;/em&gt; - 30 Jan 2025&lt;br&gt;
Sniper Elite 5 &lt;em&gt;(PC, Xbox, PS5)&lt;/em&gt; - 26 May 2022&lt;br&gt;
Hyperbrawl Tournament &lt;em&gt;(PC, Xbox, PS4, Switch)&lt;/em&gt; - 20 Oct 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I graduated high school with a Computer Science degree in Bulgaria, whilst also doing freelance 2D art. In 2016 I moved to the UK and finished a BA (Hons) in Games Design at University of Central Lancashire, Preston (UCLan). In 2019 I completed my studies with a First Class Degree and won the Games Design Student of the Year Award. I also took part in The Rookies 2019 and was picked as one of &amp;ldquo;Rookie of the Year - Finalist&amp;rdquo;. Later that year and after sending out many job applications I entered the games industry with my first job as a 3D Artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often set out on long journeys of creating real time 3D environments. Why do I say long? With all the different fields one needs to combine towards the making of a good scene it can sometimes take weeks and months to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That arduous journey is where the enjoyment comes. The process teaches you more about art and the 3D field. It also teaches you about yourself and your perception of the world outside of the camera frustum and the pixel-grid perfect screen you see on the monitor during the everyday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m here to write and share this journey, including all the little tips and tricks I discover and learn along the way. And in doing so will be sharing my creative process, the sources of my inspirations and my ambitions with each scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you find enjoyment in this and get insight into what might be new for you in creating the best 3D worlds, games, and art you dare to boldly dream of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in touch with me and send me any questions you might have over at my socials. (can be found on the website menus, but here are some)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bsky.app/profile/petedimitrovart.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://bsky.app/profile/petedimitrovart.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@PeteDimitrovArt&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@PeteDimitrovArt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@PeteDimitrov&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.youtube.com/@PeteDimitrov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/peterdimitrovart/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/peterdimitrovart/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cara.app/petedimitrovart/all&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://cara.app/petedimitrovart/all&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take care and spread kindness. 🏳️‍🌈&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Links</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/links/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/links/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the socials footer, below my profile picture on the left you will find my links. If you are on mobile, the little menu button will expand with those links for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more links on the About page, with socials I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the space to include in the above bar. In the menu there is the Portfolio page too. That will take you directly to my professional portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look below on this page though, you can find links and descriptions towards some of my friends on the web. Others in the links I&amp;rsquo;ve not had the pleasure to meet yet. I&amp;rsquo;ve put their links nonetheless, as they are people who have resources that are valuable for learning. I believe those could be useful for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>https://petedimitrovart.com/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://petedimitrovart.com/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
